<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ubuntu Security Podcast</title>
    <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ubuntu Security Podcast</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 17:31:00 +0930</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Episode 159</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-159/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 17:31:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-159/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we bring you part 2 of our look at the new Ubuntu 22.04 LTS release and what&amp;rsquo;s in it for security, plus we cover security updates for DPDK, OpenSSL, Cron, RSyslog, Curl and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 37 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5401-1] DPDK vulnerabilities [00:54]  2 CVEs addressed in Focal (20.04 LTS), Impish (21.10), Jammy (22.04 LTS)  CVE-2022-0669  CVE-2021-3839    Data-plane development kit (provides TCP offloading to userspace to accelerate package processing workloads) Used by openvswitch for OpenStack software defined networking OOB write due to missing check on queue length in vhost comms - could allow a malicious guest to crash or get code execution on the host Also fixed a possible DoS attack between a malicious vhost-user primary and secondary where the primary can spam the secondary with with a huge number of open file-descriptors which eventually leads the secondary to exhaust it&amp;rsquo;s fd limit and hence DoS  [USN-5402-1] OpenSSL vulnerabilities [01:36]  4 CVEs addressed in Bionic (18.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 157</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-157/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 11:33:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-157/</guid>
      <description>Overview Ubuntu 22.04 LTS (Jammy Jellyfish) is officially released 🎉 and so this week we take a quick look at the new features and enhancements, with a particular focus on security, plus we cover security updates for the Linux kernel, Firefox, Django, Git, Gzip and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 58 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5368-1] Linux kernel vulnerabilities [00:51]  23 CVEs addressed in Focal (20.04 LTS)  CVE-2022-27666  CVE-2022-0742  CVE-2022-0516  CVE-2022-0435  CVE-2022-0382  CVE-2022-0264  CVE-2021-45480  CVE-2021-45402  CVE-2021-45095  CVE-2021-44733  CVE-2021-43975  CVE-2021-4197  CVE-2021-4135  CVE-2021-39698  CVE-2021-39685  CVE-2021-28715  CVE-2021-28714  CVE-2021-28713  CVE-2021-28712  CVE-2021-28711  CVE-2022-0492  CVE-2022-1055  CVE-2022-23222    5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 156</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-156/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 15:52:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-156/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we bring you the TL;DL (too-long, didn&amp;rsquo;t listen 😉) version of Camila&amp;rsquo;s recent 4-part Ubuntu hardening series, plus we look at security updates for Twisted, rsync, the Linux kernel, DOSBox, Tomcat and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 48 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5354-1] Twisted vulnerabilities [00:47]  2 CVEs addressed in Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS), Impish (21.10)  CVE-2022-21716  CVE-2022-21712    No limit to the amount of memory consumed when parsing the SSH version string from a client/server - malicious client/server could then send an infinite length version and crash the corresponding server/client - limited to 4KB Cookies and auth headers exposed in cross-origin redirects - leak sensitive info  [USN-5355-1, USN-5355-2] zlib vulnerability [01:34]  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 155</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-155/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 15:36:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-155/</guid>
      <description>Overview It&amp;rsquo;s an off-by-one error in the podcast this week as we bring you part 4 of Camila&amp;rsquo;s 3-part Ubuntu hardening series, plus we look at security updates for Thunderbird, OpenVPN, Python, Paramiko and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 47 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5345-1] Thunderbird vulnerabilities [00:45]  13 CVEs addressed in Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS), Impish (21.10)  CVE-2022-0566  CVE-2022-26387  CVE-2022-26386  CVE-2022-22756  CVE-2022-22754  CVE-2022-26384  CVE-2022-26383  CVE-2022-26381  CVE-2022-22764  CVE-2022-22763  CVE-2022-22761  CVE-2022-22760  CVE-2022-22759    91.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 154</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-154/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 15:56:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-154/</guid>
      <description>Overview It&amp;rsquo;s PIE🥧 for everyone this week as Python finally becomes a position independent executable for Ubuntu 22.04, plus Camila brings you the third part in her Ubuntu server hardening guide and we cover security updates for FUSE, Bind, Apache, the Linux kernel and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 105 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5326-1] FUSE vulnerability [00:49]  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial ESM (16.04 ESM)  CVE-2018-10906    When using SELinux on Ubuntu, possible to bypass regular restrictions that would normally prevent non-root users from mounting a FUSE fs with the allow_other mount option - this option specifies all users can access files from the FUSE fs whereas normally FUSE enforces on the user which mounted the file has access Could trick another user into then accessing files from the FUSE fs  [USN-5334-1] man-db vulnerability [02:22]  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial ESM (16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 153</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-153/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 13:35:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-153/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we bring you part 2 of Camila&amp;rsquo;s guide on Ubuntu server hardening, plus we cover vulnerabilities and updates in Expat, Firefox, OpenSSL, LibreOffice and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 22 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5320-1] Expat vulnerabilities and regression [00:45]  4 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.04 ESM), Xenial ESM (16.04 ESM), Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS), Impish (21.10)  CVE-2022-25315 CVE-2022-25314 CVE-2022-25313 CVE-2022-25236   Includes a fix for a regression from the previous Expat update in USN-5288-1 (Episode 150) (CVE-2022-25236) - plus fixes for 3 additional CVEs  stack overrun through a deeply nested DTD 2 different integer overflows on crafted contents as well  ∴ buffer overflow → DoS / RCE      [USN-5321-1] Firefox vulnerabilities [01:45]  7 CVEs addressed in Bionic (18.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 151</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-151/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 15:31:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-151/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we do the usual round-up of security vulnerability fixes for the various Ubuntu releases, plus we discuss enabling PIE for Python and preview some upcoming content on Ubuntu system hardening as well.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 44 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5292-4] snapd regression [00:52]  4 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.04 ESM), Xenial ESM (16.04 ESM), Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS), Impish (21.10)  CVE-2021-44731 CVE-2021-44730 CVE-2021-4120 CVE-2021-3155   Episode 149 - another regression with fish shell  [USN-5303-1] PHP vulnerability [01:20]  1 CVEs addressed in Focal (20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 150</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-150/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 14:40:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-150/</guid>
      <description>Overview Ubuntu 20.04.4 LTS is released, plus we talk about Google Project Zero&amp;rsquo;s metrics report as well as security updates for the Linux kernel, expat, c3p0, Cyrus SASL and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 62 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5292-2, USN-5292-3] snapd vulnerabilities [00:44]  4 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.04 ESM), Xenial ESM (16.04 ESM), Focal (20.04 LTS)  CVE-2021-44731 CVE-2021-44730 CVE-2021-4120 CVE-2021-3155   Episode 149  [USN-5294-1, USN-5294-2] Linux kernel vulnerabilities [01:38]  8 CVEs addressed in Bionic (18.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 149</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-149/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 16:51:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-149/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week Qualys dominate the week in security updates, disclosing details of 4 different SUID-root vulnerabilities, including Oh Snap! More Lemmings (Local Privilege Escalation in snap-confine), plus we look at updates for Firefox, cryptsetup and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 23 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5279-1] util-linux vulnerabilities [00:59]  2 CVEs addressed in Focal (20.04 LTS), Impish (21.10)  CVE-2021-3996 CVE-2021-3995   First 2 of number of vulns discovered by Qualys this week umount and fusermount are both setuid root An unprivileged user is allowed to unmount a FUSE filesystem which is already mounted and which they own libumount parses /proc/self/mountinfo to validate if is a FUSE fs When a mount entry is deleted, the kernel appends (deleted) to the name of it in the mount table libumount strips this off when parsing mountinfo to get the actual path so a user could mount a FUSE filesystem at a mountpoint with (deleted) in the name - and then libumount will strip this off and umount the original path - ie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 148</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-148/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 14:28:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-148/</guid>
      <description>Overview It&amp;rsquo;s main vs universe as we take a deep dive into the Ubuntu archive and look at these components plus what goes into each and how the security team goes about reviewing software destined for main, plus we cover security updates for Django, BlueZ, NVIDIA Graphics Drivers and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 53 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5265-1] Linux kernel vulnerabilities [01:19]  10 CVEs addressed in Focal (20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 147</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-147/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 16:33:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-147/</guid>
      <description>Overview We&amp;rsquo;re back after a few weeks off to cover the launch of the Ubuntu Security Guide for DISA-STIG, plus we detail the latest vulnerabilities and updates for lxml, PolicyKit, the Linux Kernel, systemd, Samba and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 100 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5225-1] lxml vulnerability [00:57]  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.04 ESM), Xenial ESM (16.04 ESM), Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS), Hirsute (21.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 17:58:32 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/about/</guid>
      <description>Ubuntu Security Podcast is a weekly* podcast discussing the latest updates and developments from the Ubuntu Security Team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 146</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-146/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 17:54:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-146/</guid>
      <description>Overview Ubuntu 21.04 goes EOL soon, plus we cover security updates for Django, the Linux kernel, Apache httpd2 + Log4j2, Ghostscript and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 28 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5204-1] Django vulnerabilities [00:45]  3 CVEs addressed in Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS), Hirsute (21.04), Impish (21.10)  CVE-2021-45452 CVE-2021-45116 CVE-2021-45115   Possible to write to arbitrary locations if a plugin etc would call Storage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 145</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-145/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 16:09:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-145/</guid>
      <description>Overview The Ubuntu Security Podcast is back for 2022 and we&amp;rsquo;re starting off the year with a bang💥! This week we bring you a special interview with Kees Cook of Google and the Linux Kernel Self Protection Project discussing Linux kernel hardening upstream developments. Plus we look at security updates for Mumble, Apache Log4j2, OpenJDK and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 31 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5195-1] Mumble vulnerability [01:02]  1 CVEs addressed in Bionic (18.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 144</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-144/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 11:00:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-144/</guid>
      <description>Overview Happy holidays! This week we bring you the second part of a special two-part holiday themed feature by Camila from the Ubuntu Security team discussing how best to protect yourself and your systems from the top cyber threats faced during the holidays.
Get in contact  security@ubuntu.com #ubuntu-security on the Libera.Chat IRC network ubuntu-hardened mailing list Security section on discourse.ubuntu.com @ubuntu_sec on twitter  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 143</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-143/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 09:40:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-143/</guid>
      <description>Overview Happy holidays! This week we bring you the first part of a special two-part holiday themed feature by Camila from the Ubuntu Security team discussing the top cyber threats faced during the holidays.
Get in contact  security@ubuntu.com #ubuntu-security on the Libera.Chat IRC network ubuntu-hardened mailing list Security section on discourse.ubuntu.com @ubuntu_sec on twitter  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 142</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-142/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 17:23:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-142/</guid>
      <description>Overview Just in time for the holidays, Log4Shell comes along to wreck everyone&amp;rsquo;s weekend - so we take a deep dive into the vulnerability that has set the internet on fire, plus we cover security updates for BlueZ, Firefox, Flatpak and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 27 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5183-1] BlueZ vulnerability [00:48]  1 CVEs addressed in Bionic (18.04 LTS)  CVE-2019-8922   Heap based buffer overflow when handling overly large SDP requests - crash / possible code execution as a result  [USN-5186-1] Firefox vulnerabilities [01:08]  10 CVEs addressed in Bionic (18.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 141</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-141/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 16:27:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-141/</guid>
      <description>Overview A preview of some things to come for the Ubuntu Security Podcast plus we cover security updates for Samba, uriparser, libmodbus, MariaDB, Mailman and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 38 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5174-1] Samba vulnerabilities [00:58]  4 CVEs addressed in Bionic (18.04 LTS)  CVE-2021-3671 CVE-2020-25722 CVE-2020-25717 CVE-2016-2124   Few weeks ago published Samba updates for a range of vulns - mentioned in Episode 139 the difficulties involved in patching older Samba versions like 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 140</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-140/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 11:57:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-140/</guid>
      <description>Overview A gnarly old bug in NSS is unearthed, plus we cover security updates for ICU, the Linux kernel and ImageMagick as well.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 20 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5156-1] ICU vulnerability [00:40]  1 CVEs addressed in Focal (20.04 LTS), Hirsute (21.04)  CVE-2021-30535   Double free - originally reported in chromium but is actually in embedded copy of icu - able to be triggered on crafted content to icu, in the case of chromium this could be via a crafted webpage or similar so not too dissimilar to usual web handling issues - memory corruption -&amp;gt; code execution (but within chromium sandbox in that case)  [USN-5158-1] ImageMagick vulnerabilities [01:25]  5 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 139</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-139/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 15:19:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-139/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we put out a call for testing and feedback on proposed Samba updates for Ubuntu 18.04 LTS plus we look at security updates for Mailman, Thunderbird, LibreOffice, BlueZ and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 15 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5150-1] OpenEXR vulnerability [00:39]  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial ESM (16.04 ESM), Bionic (18.04 LTS)  CVE-2021-3941   oss-fuzz -&amp;gt; div-by-zero with crafted image using YUV-encoded colors  [USN-5151-1] Mailman vulnerabilities [00:58]  2 CVEs addressed in Xenial ESM (16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 138</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-138/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 14:21:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-138/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we discuss some of the challenges and trade-offs encountered when providing security support for ageing software, plus we discuss security updates for the Linux kernel, Firejail, Samba, PostgreSQL and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 42 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5138-1] python-py vulnerability [00:38]  1 CVEs addressed in Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS)  CVE-2020-29651   Python library providing path handling, config file parsing and other features which are now in standard lib or other packages - has been deprecated ReDoS against path handling code (regex with catastrophic backtracking)  [USN-5139-1] Linux kernel (OEM 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 137</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-137/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 14:48:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-137/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at some details of the 29 unique CVEs addressed across the supported Ubuntu releases in the past 7 days and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 29 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5131-1] Firefox vulnerabilities [00:42]  6 CVEs addressed in Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS), Hirsute (21.04), Impish (21.10)  CVE-2021-38509 CVE-2021-38508 CVE-2021-38507 CVE-2021-38506 CVE-2021-38504 CVE-2021-38503   94.0  Copy image link - copies final image URL after redirects - if a page were to then combine this with a content security policy which blocked a redirect, the image URL may then contain any authentication tokens - and so if a page could trick a user into copying and pasting that image URL into the page an attacker could steal their auth token Various web framework issues    [USN-5132-1] Thunderbird vulnerabilities [01:56]  6 CVEs addressed in Impish (21.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 136</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-136/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 15:22:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-136/</guid>
      <description>Overview The road to Ubuntu 22.04 LTS begins so we look at some of its planned features plus we cover security updates for the Linux kernel, Mailman, Apport, PHP, Bind and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 92 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5114-1] Linux kernel vulnerabilities [01:15]  4 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.04 ESM), Xenial ESM (16.04 ESM), Bionic (18.04 LTS)  CVE-2021-42008 CVE-2021-40490 CVE-2021-38198 CVE-2020-3702   4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 135</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-135/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 14:51:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-135/</guid>
      <description>Overview Ubuntu 20.04 LTS targeted at Tianfu Cup 2021 plus we cover security updates for Linux kernel, nginx, Ardour and strongSwan.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 24 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5091-3] Linux kernel (Azure) regression  6 CVEs addressed in Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS)  CVE-2021-38204 CVE-2021-38199 CVE-2021-38160 CVE-2021-37576 CVE-2021-3679 CVE-2021-33624    [USN-5092-3] Linux kernel (Azure) regression [00:50]  12 CVEs addressed in Focal (20.04 LTS), Hirsute (21.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 134</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-134/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 14:47:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-134/</guid>
      <description>Overview It&amp;rsquo;s release week! As Ubuntu 21.10 Impish Indri is released we take a look at some of the new security features it brings, plus we cover security updates for containerd, MongoDB, Mercurial, docker.io and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 58 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5095-1] Apache Commons IO vulnerability [00:46]  1 CVEs addressed in Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS)  CVE-2021-29425   Failed to properly sanitize filenames in FileNameUtils.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 133</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-133/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 15:10:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-133/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at a Wifi lookalike attack dubbed &amp;ldquo;SSID stripping&amp;rdquo; plus updates for ca-certificates, EDK II, Apache, the Linux kernel and even vim!
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 28 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5086-1] Linux kernel vulnerability [00:50]  Affecting Xenial ESM (16.04 ESM), Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS), Hirsute (21.04) s390x BPF JIT verifier bypass - no CVE assigned  [USN-5085-1] SQL parse vulnerability [01:33]  1 CVEs addressed in Hirsute (21.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 132</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-132/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 15:05:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-132/</guid>
      <description>Overview Extended Security Maintenance gets an extension, Linux disk encryption and authentication goes under the microscope and we cover security updates for libgcrypt, the Linux kernel, Python, and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 20 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5078-2] Squashfs-Tools vulnerabilities [01:02]  2 CVEs addressed in Xenial ESM (16.04 ESM)  CVE-2021-41072 CVE-2021-40153   Episode 131  [USN-5080-1, USN-5080-2] Libgcrypt vulnerabilities [01:43]  2 CVEs addressed in Xenial ESM (16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 131</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-131/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 13:55:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-131/</guid>
      <description>Overview OWASP Top 10 gets updated for 2021 and we look at security vulnerabilities in the Linux kernel, Ghostscript, Git, curl and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 26 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5069-2] mod-auth-mellon vulnerability [00:43]  1 CVEs addressed in Hirsute (21.04)  CVE-2021-3639   Episode 130 - failed to properly handle crafted redirect links -&amp;gt; open redirect  [USN-5070-1] Linux kernel vulnerabilities  10 CVEs addressed in Focal (20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 130</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-130/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 14:21:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-130/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we discuss compiler warnings as build errors in the Linux kernel, plus we look at security updates for HAProxy, GNU cpio, PySAML2, mod-auth-mellon and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 15 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5051-4] OpenSSL regression [00:51]  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.04 ESM)  CVE-2021-3712   Episode 129 Original backport of patch contained a typo which introduced a regression where ASN1_STRINGs would fail to print in some cases  [USN-5062-1] Linux kernel vulnerability [01:20]  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 129</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-129/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 14:23:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-129/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at a malware campaign associated with the popular Krita painting application, plus we cover security updates for MongoDB, libssh, Squashfs-Tools, Thunderbird and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 17 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5037-2] Firefox regression [00:47]  Affecting Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS), Hirsute (21.04) 91.0.2 - upstream bug where as part of their advanced privacy protection, would purge cookies associated with ad trackers etc - but this would then clear authentication data as well and so would lose your master password for Lockwise - and hence prompt the re-enter it seemingly randomly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 128</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-128/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 12:23:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-128/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we dive into Trend Micro&amp;rsquo;s recent Linux Threat Report and the release of Ubuntu 20.04.3 LTS, plus we detail security updates for Inetutils telnetd, the Linux kernel and OpenSSL.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 9 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5048-1] Inetutils vulnerability [00:45]  1 CVEs addressed in Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS)  CVE-2020-10188   Buffer overflow in inetutils telnetd - originally CVE was found in netkit telnetd - but subsequently the GNU inetutils version was also found to contain basically the same vulnerable function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 127</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-127/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 12:47:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-127/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at security updates for Firefox, PostgreSQL, MariaDB, HAProxy, the Linux kernel and more, plus we cover some current openings on the team - come join us ☺
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 35 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5037-1] Firefox vulnerabilities [00:39]  10 CVEs addressed in Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS), Hirsute (21.04)  CVE-2021-29990 CVE-2021-29989 CVE-2021-29988 CVE-2021-29987 CVE-2021-29986 CVE-2021-29985 CVE-2021-29984 CVE-2021-29982 CVE-2021-29981 CVE-2021-29980   91.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 126</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-126/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 15:04:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-126/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week Ubuntu 20.04 LTS was FIPS 140-2 certified plus the AppArmor project made some point releases, and we released security updates for Docker, Perl, c-ares, GPSd and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 2 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5031-1] openCryptoki vulnerability [00:54]  Affecting Hirsute (21.04) PKCS#11 daemon Bug fix that was deemed to have security implications - so was going to be done via SRU for 21.04 but instead we published via -security to ensure all users received it Thanks to Simon Chopin from Foundations team for preparing this update  [USN-5032-1, USN-5032-2] Docker vulnerabilities [02:29]  Affecting Bionic (18.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 125</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-125/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 16:02:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-125/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we discuss new kernel memory hardening and security development proposals from Ubuntu Security Alumnus Kees Cook, plus we look at details of security updates for WebKitGTK, libsndfile, GnuTLS, exiv2 and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 22 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5024-1] WebKitGTK vulnerabilities [00:57]  13 CVEs addressed in Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS), Hirsute (21.04)  CVE-2021-30799 CVE-2021-30797 CVE-2021-30795 CVE-2021-30758 CVE-2021-30749 CVE-2021-30744 CVE-2021-30734 CVE-2021-30720 CVE-2021-30689 CVE-2021-30665 CVE-2021-30663 CVE-2021-21779 CVE-2021-21775   Every 5-10 weeks so time for another one Usual web / js engine issues - XSS, DoS, RCE etc  [USN-4944-2] MariaDB regression [01:30]  Affecting Focal (20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 124</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-124/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 14:46:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-124/</guid>
      <description>Overview It&amp;rsquo;s another week when too many security updates are never enough as we cover 240 CVE fixes across Avahi, QEMU, the Linux kernel, containerd, binutils and more, plus the Ubuntu 20.10 Groovy Gorilla end-of-life.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 240 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5008-1, USN-5008-2] Avahi vulnerabilities [00:36]  2 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.04 ESM), Xenial ESM (16.04 ESM), Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS), Groovy (20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 123</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-123/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 13:48:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-123/</guid>
      <description>Overview Is npm audit more harm than good? Plus this week we look at security updates for DjVuLibre, libuv, PHP and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 8 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4905-2] X.Org X Server vulnerability [00:42]  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.04 ESM)  CVE-2021-3472   Episode 112 - Local user (X client) could crash the server via Xinput extension and ChangeFeedbackControl request - integer underflow -&amp;gt; heap buffer overflow  [USN-5005-1] DjVuLibre vulnerability [01:26]  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial ESM (16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 122</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-122/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 16:14:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-122/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at some new Linux kernel security features including the Landlock LSM and Core Scheduling plus we cover security updates for RabbitMQ, Ceph, Thunderbird and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 46 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5004-1] RabbitMQ vulnerabilities [00:44]  2 CVEs addressed in Xenial ESM (16.04 ESM), Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS), Groovy (20.10), Hirsute (21.04)  CVE-2021-22116 CVE-2019-11287   AMQP server written in Erlang Possible to cause the server to consume excessive memory by sending large values in the X-Reason HTTP header - resource exhaustion - DoS Possible infinite loop - failed to perform sufficient validation - DoS  [USN-4998-1] Ceph vulnerabilities [01:38]  7 CVEs addressed in Focal (20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 121</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-121/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 12:36:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-121/</guid>
      <description>Overview Ubuntu One opens up two-factor authentication for all, plus we cover security updates for Nettle, libxml2, GRUB2, the Linux kernel and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 73 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4989-2] BlueZ vulnerabilities [00:57]  2 CVEs addressed in Xenial ESM (16.04 ESM)  CVE-2020-27153 CVE-2020-26558   Episode 120 - bluetooth spec issue around pairing takeover plus a possible double-free in gattool that is likely quite hard to exploit due to time window race between the two free() calls  [USN-4990-1] Nettle vulnerabilities [01:27]  2 CVEs addressed in Bionic (18.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 120</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-120/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 16:21:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-120/</guid>
      <description>Overview In this week&amp;rsquo;s episode we look at how to get media coverage for your shiny new vulnerability, plus we cover security updates for ExifTool, ImageMagick, BlueZ and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 49 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4986-2] rpcbind vulnerability [00:44]  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.04 ESM), Xenial ESM (16.04 ESM)  CVE-2017-8779   Episode 119 (bionic) - memory leak on crafted requests  [USN-4986-3, USN-4986-4] rpcbind regression [01:11]  Affecting Trusty ESM (14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 119</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-119/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 10:53:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-119/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we cover security updates for the Linux kernel, PolicyKit, Intel Microcode and more, plus we look at a report of an apparent malicious snap in the Snap Store and some of the mechanics behind snap confinement.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 42 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4979-1] Linux kernel vulnerabilities [01:04]  13 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.04 ESM), Xenial (16.04 LTS), Bionic (18.04 LTS)  CVE-2021-3483 CVE-2021-3428 CVE-2021-33033 CVE-2021-31916 CVE-2021-29647 CVE-2021-28972 CVE-2021-28971 CVE-2021-28964 CVE-2021-28660 CVE-2020-25673 CVE-2020-25672 CVE-2020-25671 CVE-2020-25670   4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 118</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-118/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 15:04:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-118/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at DMCA notices sent against Ubuntu ISOs plus security updates for nginx, DHCP, Lasso, Django, Dnsmasq and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 24 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4967-1, USN-4967-2] nginx vulnerability [00:50]  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.04 ESM), Xenial (16.04 LTS), Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS), Groovy (20.10), Hirsute (21.04)  CVE-2021-23017   1 byte buffer overflow, able to be trigged by a crafted DNS response - UDP so could possibly be more easily forged than TCP (less state) - crash, RCE  [USN-4968-1, USN-4968-2] LZ4 vulnerability [01:27]  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 117</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-117/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 17:21:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-117/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we&amp;rsquo;re talking about moving IRC networks plus security updates for Pillow, Babel, Apport, X11 and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 24 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4963-1] Pillow vulnerabilities [00:55]  6 CVEs addressed in Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS), Groovy (20.10), Hirsute (21.04)  CVE-2021-28678 CVE-2021-28677 CVE-2021-28676 CVE-2021-28675 CVE-2021-25288 CVE-2021-25287   Python image handling library - used by many other packages for their image handling All DoS issues via OOB read and similar so not critical  [USN-4962-1] Babel vulnerability [01:31]  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 116</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-116/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 13:41:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-116/</guid>
      <description>Overview With 60 CVEs fixed across MySQL, Django, Please and the Linux kernel this week we take a look at some of these details, plus look at the recent announcement of 1Password for Linux and some open positions on the team too.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 60 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4952-1] MySQL vulnerabilities [00:58]  33 CVEs addressed in Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS), Groovy (20.10), Hirsute (21.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 115</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-115/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 14:49:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-115/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at some details of the 90 unique CVEs addressed across the supported Ubuntu releases and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 90 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4934-2] Exim vulnerabilities [00:41]  16 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.04 ESM), Xenial (16.04 LTS)  CVE-2021-27216 CVE-2020-28025 CVE-2020-28024 CVE-2020-28022 CVE-2020-28020 CVE-2020-28017 CVE-2020-28016 CVE-2020-28015 CVE-2020-28014 CVE-2020-28013 CVE-2020-28012 CVE-2020-28011 CVE-2020-28009 CVE-2020-28008 CVE-2020-28007 CVE-2020-28026   Episode 114  [USN-4937-1] GNOME Autoar vulnerability [01:00]  1 CVEs addressed in Bionic (18.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 114</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-114/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:03:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-114/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at the response from the Linux Technical Advisory Board to the UMN Linux kernel incident, plus we cover the 21Nails Exim vulnerabilities as well as updates for Bind, Samba, OpenVPN and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 40 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4928-1] GStreamer Good Plugins vulnerabilities [00:40]  2 CVEs addressed in Xenial (16.04 LTS), Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS), Groovy (20.10)  CVE-2021-3498 CVE-2021-3497   UAF or heap corruption when handling crafted Matroska files - crash / RCE  [USN-4929-1] Bind vulnerabilities [01:18]  3 CVEs addressed in Xenial (16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 113</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-113/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 14:33:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-113/</guid>
      <description>Overview With 21 CVEs fixed this week we look at updates for Dnsmasq, Firefox, OpenJDK and more, plus we discuss the recent release of Ubuntu 21.04 and malicious commits in the upstream Linux kernel.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 21 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4916-2] Linux kernel regression [00:48]  2 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.04 ESM), Xenial (16.04 LTS), Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS)  CVE-2021-29154 CVE-2021-3493   Possible memory leak introduced via fix for overlayfs priv esc vuln - so the fix effectively introduced a new vuln but only a DoS not priv esc  [USN-4924-1] Dnsmasq vulnerabilities [01:17]  2 CVEs addressed in Xenial (16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 112</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-112/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 17:18:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-112/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at a reboot of the DWF project, Rust in the Linux kernel, an Ubuntu security webinar plus some details of the 45 CVEs addressed across the Ubuntu releases this last week and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 45 unique CVEs addressed
[LSN-0075-1] Linux kernel vulnerability [01:01]  8 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.04 ESM), Xenial (16.04 LTS), Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS)  CVE-2021-27365 CVE-2021-27364 CVE-2021-27363 CVE-2021-3444 CVE-2020-29374 CVE-2020-29372 CVE-2020-27171 CVE-2020-27170   madvise issue reported by Jann Horn - BPF spectre mitigations fixes (Episode 109)  [USN-4903-1] curl vulnerability [02:02]  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 111</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-111/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 12:04:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-111/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at how Ubuntu is faring at Pwn2Own 2021 (which still has 1 day and 2 more attempts at pwning Ubuntu 20.10 to go) plus we look at security updates for SpamAssassin, the Linux kernel, Rack and Django, and we cover some open positions on the Ubuntu Security team too.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 14 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4899-1] SpamAssassin vulnerability [00:46]  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial (16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 110</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-110/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 11:38:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-110/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at 2 years of 14.04 ESM, a kernel Livepatch issue, DNS-over-HTTPS for Google Chrome plus security updates for ldb, OpenSSL, Squid, curl and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 38 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4888-1, USN-4888-2] ldb vulnerabilities [01:06]  2 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.04 ESM), Xenial (16.04 LTS), Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS), Groovy (20.10)  CVE-2020-27840 CVE-2021-20277   In the ldb package but was reported by Samba - libldb provides an LDAP-like database - is used internally by Samba etc - and whilst the Samba package contains a copy of ldb internally we don&amp;rsquo;t compile this in Ubuntu, instead we link it against the ldb package in the repo so we only have to patch a CVE in one place Heap buffer overflow when parsing a DN string with lots of trailing whitespace - allows to place a single NUL byte at a chosen offset before an allocated buffer Heap buffer overflow when parsing an LDAP attribute string with multiple consecutive leading spaces - memmove() to a location beyond the end of the buffer Crash -&amp;gt; DoS, can&amp;rsquo;t rule out RCE due to nature of heap buffer overflows  [USN-4889-1] Linux kernel vulnerabilities [02:49]  3 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 109</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-109/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 21:38:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-109/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at security updates for containerd, Ruby, the Linux kernel, Pygments and more, plus we cover some open positions within the team as well.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 28 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4881-1] containerd vulnerability [00:38]  1 CVEs addressed in Focal (20.04 LTS), Groovy (20.10)  CVE-2021-21334   When using the containerd CRI implementation (kubernetes container runtime interface) - would share environment variables etc between containers that shared the same image - so could allow an inadvertent info leak from one container to another - race condition so would be less likely to occur if not launching containers in rapid succession which share the same image  [USN-4882-1] Ruby vulnerabilities [01:27]  3 CVEs addressed in Xenial (16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 108</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-108/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 11:19:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-108/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we start preparing for 16.04 LTS to transition to Extended Security Maintenance, plus we look at security updates for OpenSSH, Python, the Linux kernel and more, as well as some currently open positions on our team.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 28 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4762-1] OpenSSH vulnerability [00:54]  1 CVEs addressed in Focal (20.04 LTS), Groovy (20.10)  CVE-2021-28041   Double free in ssh-agent - so only affects openssh-client and where the ssh-agent socket is able to be accessed by other users etc - on moderns systems the socket is only accessible by the owner so would need to have forwarded the ssh-agent to an attacker controlled host perhaps to be vulnerable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 107</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-107/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 15:49:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-107/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we check on the status of the pending GRUB2 Secure Boot updates and detail some open positions within the team, plus we look at security updates for GLib, zstd, Go, Git and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 7 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4757-2] wpa_supplicant and hostapd vulnerability [00:45]  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.04 ESM)  CVE-2021-27803   P2P/wifi direct UAF -&amp;gt; crash, RCE from Episode 106  [USN-4733-2] GNOME Autoar regression [01:23]  Affecting Bionic (18.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 106</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-106/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 15:38:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-106/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we talk about more BootHole-like vulnerabilities in GRUB2, a Spectre exploit found in-the-wild, security updates for xterm, screen, Python, wpa_supplicant and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 52 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4698-2] Dnsmasq regression [00:44]  8 CVEs addressed in Xenial (16.04 LTS), Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS), Groovy (20.10)  CVE-2019-14834 CVE-2020-25686 CVE-2020-25685 CVE-2020-25684 CVE-2020-25683 CVE-2020-25682 CVE-2020-25687 CVE-2020-25681   Relates to a dnsmasq update done back in January - upstream fixes results in regressions in some network environments - backported the resulting additional fixes from upstream to resolve these  [USN-4746-1] xterm vulnerability [01:14]  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial (16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 105</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-105/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 15:38:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-105/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we discuss security updates in Linux Mint, Google funding Linux kernel security development and details for security updates in BIND, OpenSSL, Jackson, OpenLDAP and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 14 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4737-1] Bind vulnerability [00:45]  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial (16.04 LTS), Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS), Groovy (20.10)  CVE-2020-8625   If using GSS-TSIG could be vulnerable to a DoS or possible RCE - this option is not enabled by default BUT is often used when bind is integrated with Samba or with a AD-DC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 104</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-104/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 22:44:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-104/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we take a look at a long-awaited update of Thunderbird in Ubuntu 20.04LTS, plus security updates for Open vSwitch, JUnit 4, PostSRSd, GNOME Autoar and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 14 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4729-1] Open vSwitch vulnerability [00:55]  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial (16.04 LTS), Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS), Groovy (20.10)  CVE-2020-35498   Most convoluted CVE description: A vulnerability was found in openvswitch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 103</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-103/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 14:07:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-103/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we take a deep dive look at 2 recent vulnerabilities in the popular application containerisation frameworks, snapd and flatpak, plus we cover security updates for MiniDLNA, PHP-PEAR, the Linux kernel and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 26 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4720-2] Apport vulnerabilities [00:53]  3 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.04 ESM)  CVE-2021-25684 CVE-2021-25683 CVE-2021-25682   Episode 102  [USN-4721-1] Flatpak vulnerability [01:06]  1 CVEs addressed in Bionic (18.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 102</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-102/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 13:31:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-102/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we discuss the recent high profile vulnerability found in libcrypt 1.9.0, plus we look at updates for the Linux kernel, XStream, Django, Apport and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 66 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4705-2] Sudo vulnerability [00:48]  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM (12.04 ESM), Trusty ESM (14.04 ESM)  CVE-2021-3156   Episode 101  [USN-4708-1] Linux kernel vulnerabilities  5 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 101</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 19:42:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-101/</guid>
      <description>Overview In the first episode for 2021 we bring back Joe McManus to discuss the SolarWinds hack plus we look at vulnerabilities in sudo, NVIDIA graphics drivers and mutt. We also cover some open positions in the team and say farewell to long-time Ubuntu Security superstar Jamie Strandboge.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 22 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4689-3] NVIDIA graphics drivers vulnerabilities [01:09]  3 CVEs addressed in Bionic (18.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 100</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-100/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 17:26:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-100/</guid>
      <description>Overview For the last episode of 2020, we look back at the most &amp;ldquo;popular&amp;rdquo; packages on this podcast for this year as well as the biggest vulnerabilities from 2020, plus a BootHole presentation at Ubuntu Masters as well as vulnerability fixes from the past week too.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 21 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4660-1] Linux kernel vulnerabilities [01:04]  10 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.04 ESM), Xenial (16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 99</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-99/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 13:45:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-99/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at security updates for Mutt, Thunderbird, Poppler, QEMU, containerd, Linux kernel &amp;amp; more, plus we discuss the 2020 State of the Octoverse Security Report from Github, Launchpad GPG keyserver migration, a new AppArmor release &amp;amp; some open positions on the team.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 68 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4645-1] Mutt vulnerability [00:59]  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM (12.04 ESM), Xenial (16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 98</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-98/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 14:38:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-98/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at updates for c-ares, PulseAudio, phpMyAdmin and more, plus we cover security news from the Ubuntu community including planning for 16.04 LTS to transition to ESM, libgcrypt FIPS cerified for 18.04 LTS and a proposal for making home directories more secure for upcoming Ubuntu releases as well.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 48 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4638-1] c-ares vulnerability [01:00]  1 CVEs addressed in Groovy (20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 97</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-97/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 12:13:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-97/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at vulnerabilities in MoinMoin, OpenLDAP, Kerberos, Raptor (including a discussion of CVE workflows and the oss-security mailing list) and more, whilst in community news we talk about the upcoming AppArmor webinar, migration of Ubuntu CVE information to ubuntu.com and reverse engineering of malware by the Canonical Sustaining Engineering team.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 45 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4629-1] MoinMoin vulnerabilities [00:50]  2 CVEs addressed in Xenial (16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 96</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-96/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 12:35:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-96/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at results from the Tianfu Cup 2020, the PLATYPUS attack against Intel CPUs, a detailed writeup of the GDM/accountsservice vulnerabilities covered in Episode 95 and more.
Goings on in Ubuntu Security Community Tianfu Cup 2020 [00:37]  https://www.zdnet.com/article/windows-10-ios-chrome-and-many-others-fall-at-chinas-top-hacking-contest/ QEMU on Ubuntu, Firefox and docker all pwned (as well as Chrome, Safari, VMWare ESXi, CentOS 8, iPhone etc) qemu-kvm on Ubuntu - used a UAF and an info-leak to escape VM and get root code exec on host - by Xiao Wei from 360 ESG Vuln Research Institute who has previously found lots of QEMU bugs - $60k Still waiting on upstream qemu / docker to release details - Firefox already patched in CVE-2020-26950  Github writeup of GDM/accountsservice vulnerabilities [02:53]  We covered the vulns in last week&amp;rsquo;s Episode 95 Kevin Backhouse provides a great amount of detail and a cool demo video of the attack - https://securitylab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 95</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-95/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 15:37:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-95/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at vulnerabilities in Samba, GDM, AccountsService, GOsa and more, plus we cover some AppArmor related Ubuntu Security community updates as well.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 26 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4552-3] Pam-python regression [00:40]  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial (16.04 LTS), Bionic (18.04 LTS)  CVE-2019-16729   Original update (Episode 92 - bionic), (Episode 94 - xenial) caused was too restrictive and would disallow PAM modules written in python from importing python modules from site-specific directories  [USN-4609-1] GOsa vulnerabilities [01:18]  3 CVEs addressed in Xenial (16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 94</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 16:14:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-94/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we cover news of the CITL drop of 7000 &amp;ldquo;vulnerabilities&amp;rdquo;, the Ubuntu Security disclosure and embargo policy plus we look at security updates for pip, blueman, the Linux kernel and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 117 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4596-1] Tomcat vulnerabilities [01:01]  4 CVEs addressed in Focal (20.04 LTS)  CVE-2020-9484 CVE-2020-13935 CVE-2020-13934 CVE-2020-11996    [USN-4587-1] iTALC vulnerabilities  19 CVEs addressed in Xenial (16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 93</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 15:08:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-93/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we cover security updates for NTP, Brotli, Spice, the Linux kernel (including BleedingTooth) and a FreeType vulnerability which is being exploited in-the-wild, plus we talk about the NSAs report into the most exploited vulnerabilities as well as the release of Ubuntu 20.10 Groovy Gorilla.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 74 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4559-1] Samba update [01:04]  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial (16.04 LTS), Bionic (18.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 92</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 10:14:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-92/</guid>
      <description>Overview It&amp;rsquo;s CVE bankruptcy! With a deluge of CVEs to cover from the last 2 weeks, we take a particular look at the ZeroLogon vulnerability in Samba this week, plus Alex covers the AppArmor 3 release and some recent / upcoming webinars hosted by the Ubuntu Security team.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 121 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4510-1, USN-4510-2] Samba vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.04 ESM), Xenial (16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 91</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-91/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 16:51:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-91/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at security updates for GUPnP, OpenJPEG, bsdiff and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 24 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4488-2] X.Org X Server vulnerabilities [00:31]  5 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.04 ESM)  CVE-2020-14345 CVE-2020-14362 CVE-2020-14361 CVE-2020-14347 CVE-2020-14346   Episode 90  [LSN-0071-1] Linux kernel vulnerability [00:50]  1 CVEs addressed in Bionic (18.04 LTS)  CVE-2020-14386   Episode 90 (AF_PACKET OOB write - crash / code exec) Also affects Focal (20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 90</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-90/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 15:26:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-90/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at security updates for the X server, the Linux kernel and GnuTLS plus we preview the upcoming AppArmor3 release that is slated for Ubuntu 20.10 (Groovy Gorilla).
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 20 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4487-1, USN-4487-2] libx11 vulnerabilities [00:58]  2 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM (12.04 ESM), Trusty ESM (14.04 ESM), Xenial (16.04 LTS), Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS)  CVE-2020-14363 CVE-2020-14344   2 privilege escalation attacks  integer overflow -&amp;gt; double free -&amp;gt; memory corruption integer overflow -&amp;gt; heap buffer overflow privilege escalation may be possible since in both cases could cause arbitrary code exec with a binary that is using libX11 and running with root privileges (setuid / sudo etc) - this is why we often advise don&amp;rsquo;t run graphical applications via sudo etc    [USN-4488-1, USN-4490-1] X.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 89</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 17:20:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-89/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we farewell Joe McManus plus we look at security updates for Firefox, Chrony, Squid, Django, the Linux kernel and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 59 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4473-1] libmysofa vulnerabilities [01:01]  5 CVEs addressed in Bionic (18.04 LTS)  CVE-2019-16095 CVE-2019-16094 CVE-2019-16093 CVE-2019-16092 CVE-2019-16091   OOB, NULL ptr deref, heap buffer overflow etc -&amp;gt; DoS  [USN-4474-1] Firefox vulnerabilities [01:30]  8 CVEs addressed in Xenial (16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 88</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 16:16:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-88/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we talk antivirus scanners and false positives in the Ubuntu archive, plus we look at security updates for QEMU, Bind, Net-SNMP, sane-backends and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 56 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4467-1] QEMU vulnerabilities [00:52]  13 CVEs addressed in Xenial (16.04 LTS), Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS)  CVE-2020-16092 CVE-2020-15863 CVE-2020-14415 CVE-2020-13800 CVE-2020-13765 CVE-2020-13754 CVE-2020-13659 CVE-2020-13362 CVE-2020-13361 CVE-2020-13253 CVE-2020-12829 CVE-2020-10761 CVE-2020-10756   OOB read in SLiRP networking implementation when replying to a ICMP ping echo request -&amp;gt; malicious guest could leak host memory -&amp;gt; info leak Network Block Device server assertion failure able to be triggered via a remote NBD client -&amp;gt; DoS Malicious guest could cause a OOB write / read in SM501 graphic driver on host -&amp;gt; crash / code exec  [USN-4466-2] curl vulnerability [01:58]  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 87</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 14:10:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-87/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at the Drovorub Linux malware outed by the NSA/FBI plus we detail security updates for Dovecot, Apache, Salt, the Linux kernel and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 24 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4456-1, USN-4456-2] Dovecot vulnerabilities [00:46]  3 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.04 ESM), Xenial (16.04 LTS), Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS)  CVE-2020-12674 CVE-2020-12673 CVE-2020-12100   3 DoS issues - nested MIME -&amp;gt; resource exhaustion, Compuserve RPA auth mechanism (rare) -&amp;gt; zero length message -&amp;gt; assert fail, NTLM missing length check -&amp;gt; buffer over read -&amp;gt; crash  [USN-4457-1, USN-4457-2] Software Properties vulnerability [01:39]  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 86</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 15:05:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-86/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we discuss the recent announcement of a long-awaited native client for 1password, plus Google Chrome experiments with anti-phishing techniques, and we take a look at security updates for OpenJDK 8, Samba, NSS and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 13 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4453-1] OpenJDK 8 vulnerabilities [01:03]  8 CVEs addressed in Xenial (16.04 LTS), Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS)  CVE-2020-14621 CVE-2020-14593 CVE-2020-14583 CVE-2020-14581 CVE-2020-14579 CVE-2020-14578 CVE-2020-14577 CVE-2020-14556   Usual mix of issues for a Java update - sandbox escape, DoS, information disclosure etc  [USN-4451-2] ppp vulnerability [01:29]  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM (12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 85</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 17:40:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-85/</guid>
      <description>Overview Dr. Levi Perigo is our special guest this week to discuss SDN and NFV with Joe, plus Alex does the weekly roundup of security updates, including Ghostscript, Squid, Apport, Whoopsie, libvirt and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 37 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4444-1] WebKitGTK vulnerabilities [00:48]  6 CVEs addressed in Bionic (18.04 LTS), Focal (20.04 LTS)  CVE-2020-9925 CVE-2020-9915 CVE-2020-9895 CVE-2020-9894 CVE-2020-9893 CVE-2020-9862   Various issues in web / JS engines - remote attacker with a malicious website could cause XSS, DoS, RCE etc  [USN-4445-1] Ghostscript vulnerability [01:22]  1 CVEs addressed in Focal (20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 84</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-84/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 16:00:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-84/</guid>
      <description>Overview In a week when too many security updates are never enough, we cover the biggest one of them all for a while, BootHole, with an interview between Joe McManus and Alex Murray for some behind-the-scenes and in-depth coverage, plus we also look briefly at the other 100-odd CVEs for the week in FFmpeg, OpenJDK, LibVNCServer, ClamAV and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 109 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4428-1] Python vulnerabilities [01:03]  4 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM (12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 83</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-83/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 15:48:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-83/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week Joe talks Linux Security Modules stacking with John Johansen and Steve Beattie plus Alex looks at security updates for snapd, the Linux kernel and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 24 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4199-2] libvpx vulnerabilities [01:05]  3 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.04 ESM)  CVE-2019-9433 CVE-2019-9232 CVE-2017-13194   VP8/VP9 video code (webm) Various OOB read on crafted input  [USN-4424-1] snapd vulnerabilities [01:38]  2 CVEs addressed in Xenial (16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 82</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-82/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 15:57:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-82/</guid>
      <description>Overview With Ubuntu 19.10 going EOL, we have a special interview by Joe with Chris Coulson and Steve Beattie from the Ubuntu Security Team to talk TPMs and Ubuntu Core 20, plus Alex looks at some of the 71 CVEs addressed by the team and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 71 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4407-1] LibVNCServer vulnerabilities [01:02]  5 CVEs addressed in Xenial (16.04 LTS), Bionic (18.04 LTS), Eoan (19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 81</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-81/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 12:28:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-81/</guid>
      <description>Overview Joe talks cyber security policy with Dr David Reed from CU Boulder, plus Alex covers the week in security updates including Mutt, NVIDIA graphics drivers, Mailman and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 6 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4403-1] Mutt vulnerability and regression [00:40]  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM (12.04 ESM), Xenial (16.04 LTS), Bionic (18.04 LTS), Eoan (19.10), Focal (20.04 LTS)  CVE-2020-14954   When connecting to an IMAP/SMTP/POP3 server via STARTTLS, would read additional data after the clear-text command to begin TLS - if someone was able to intercept the connection they could inject content which would then later get processed by Mutt as though it had come from the TLS connection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 80</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-80/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 15:21:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-80/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week, Sid Faber and Kyle Fazzari of the Ubuntu Robotics team interview Vijay Sarvepalli from CERT about the recent Ripple20 vulnerabilities announcement, plus we look at security updates for Bind, Mutt, curl and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 8 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4397-2] NSS vulnerability [00:40]  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM (12.04 ESM), Trusty ESM (14.04 ESM)  CVE-2020-12399   Episode 79 - timing side-channel attack during DSA key generation  [USN-4399-1] Bind vulnerabilities [01:00]  2 CVEs addressed in Focal (20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 79</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-79/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 16:06:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-79/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week Joe discusses Intel&amp;rsquo;s CET announcement with John Johansen, plus Alex details recent security fixes including SQLite, fwupd, NSS, DBus and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 24 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4394-1] SQLite vulnerabilities [00:56]  9 CVEs addressed in Xenial (16.04 LTS), Bionic (18.04 LTS), Eoan (19.10), Focal (20.04 LTS)  CVE-2020-13632 CVE-2020-13631 CVE-2020-13630 CVE-2020-13435 CVE-2020-13434 CVE-2020-11655 CVE-2019-19645 CVE-2019-19603 CVE-2018-8740   NULL ptr deref via crafted query, UAF, OOB read, integer overflow when printing high precision floating point numbers, various minor issues when handling crafted databases  [USN-4385-2] Intel Microcode regression [01:43]  3 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 78</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-78/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 16:23:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-78/</guid>
      <description>Overview SRBDS aka CrossTalk, the latest Intel speculative execution attack, is the big news this week in security updates for Ubuntu, as well as fixes for GnuTLS, Firefox and more, plus Alex and Joe talk about using STRIDE for threat modelling of software products.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 39 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4381-2] Django vulnerabilities [01:00]  2 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM (14.04 ESM)  CVE-2020-13596 CVE-2020-13254   Episode 77  [USN-4382-1] FreeRDP vulnerabilities [01:28]  14 CVEs addressed in Xenial (16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 77</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-77/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 17:39:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-77/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at security updates for Unbound, OpenSSL, Flask, FreeRDP, Django and more, plus Joe and Alex discuss the Octopus malware infecting Netbeans projects.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 40 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4374-1] Unbound vulnerabilities  2 CVEs addressed in Bionic (18.04 LTS), Eoan (19.10), Focal (20.04 LTS)  CVE-2020-12663 CVE-2020-12662   NXNS attack (Episode 75) (form of DNS reflection attack) Infinite loop when processing malformed answers from upstream servers -&amp;gt; CPU DoS  [USN-4375-1] PHP vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM (12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 76</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-76/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 15:10:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-76/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we welcome back Vineetha Kamath, Ubuntu Security Certifications Manager, to discuss the recent release of FIPS modules for Ubuntu 18.04 LTS and we look at security updates for Bind, ClamAV, QEMU, the Linux kernel and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 24 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4365-2] Bind vulnerabilities [00:37]  2 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM (12.04 ESM), Trusty ESM (14.04 ESM)  CVE-2020-8617 CVE-2020-8616   Episode 75 - https://nxnsattack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 75</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-75/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 16:55:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-75/</guid>
      <description>Overview In episode 75 we look at security updates for APT, json-c, Bind, the Linux kernel and more, plus Joe and Alex discuss recent phishing attacks and the Wired biopic of Marcus Hutchins.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 26 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4358-1] libexif vulnerabilities [00:44]  2 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM (12.04 ESM), Trusty ESM (14.04 ESM), Xenial (16.04 LTS), Bionic (18.04 LTS), Eoan (19.10), Focal (20.04 LTS)  CVE-2020-12767 CVE-2018-20030   Divide by zero and a CPU infinite loop (DoS) for handling crafted exif content  [USN-4359-1] APT vulnerability [01:19]  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial (16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 74</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-74/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 16:36:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-74/</guid>
      <description>Overview Special guest, Tim McNamara, author of Rust In Action talks all things Rust plus we look at security updates for Linux bluetooth firmware, OpenLDAP, PulseAudio, Squid and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 17 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4351-1] Linux firmware vulnerability [01:03]  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial (16.04 LTS), Bionic (18.04 LTS)  CVE-2018-5383   Bluetooth devices failed to properly validate elliptic curve parameters used in key exchange - remote attacker could possibly force a weak key to be used and hence obtain the encryption key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 158</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-158/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 16:46:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-158/</guid>
      <description>Overview Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Nimbuspwn sets the Linux security media ablaze but where there&amp;rsquo;s smoke there&amp;rsquo;s not always fire, plus we bring you the first part of a 2 part series looking at some of the security features in the latest Ubuntu 22.04 LTS release.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 92 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5381-1] Linux kernel (OEM) vulnerabilities  11 CVEs addressed in Focal (20.04 LTS)  CVE-2022-28356  CVE-2022-27223  CVE-2022-26966  CVE-2022-26490  CVE-2022-24958  CVE-2022-1048  CVE-2022-1016  CVE-2022-1011  CVE-2022-0854  CVE-2022-0494  CVE-2022-1015     [USN-5383-1] Linux kernel vulnerabilities  8 CVEs addressed in Focal (20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 152</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-152/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 14:19:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-152/</guid>
      <description>Overview It&amp;rsquo;s a big week for kernel security vulnerabilities - we cover Dirty Pipe and fixes for the latest microarchitectural side channel issues, plus we bring you the first in a 3 part series on hardening your Ubuntu systems against malicious attackers.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 34 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-5312-1] HAProxy vulnerability [00:46]  1 CVEs addressed in Focal (20.04 LTS), Impish (21.10)  CVE-2022-0711   CPU based DoS via the Set-Cookie2 header - obsolete HTTP response header used to send cookies from the server to the user - possible infinite loop when parsing responses which contained this header  [USN-5300-2, USN-5300-3] PHP vulnerabilities [01:24]  6 CVEs addressed in Bionic (18.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 17:58:29 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/contact/</guid>
      <description> security@ubuntu.com #ubuntu-security on the Libera.Chat IRC network ubuntu-hardened mailing list Security section on discourse.ubuntu.com @ubuntu_sec on twitter  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 73</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-73/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 16:33:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-73/</guid>
      <description>Overview After the recent release of Ubuntu 20.04 LTS, we look at security fixes for OpenJDK, CUPS, the Linux kernel, Samba and more, plus Joe and Alex discuss robot kits and the Kaiji botnet.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 86 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4337-1] OpenJDK vulnerabilities [01:21]  13 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Eoan  CVE-2020-2830 CVE-2020-2816 CVE-2020-2805 CVE-2020-2803 CVE-2020-2800 CVE-2020-2781 CVE-2020-2778 CVE-2020-2773 CVE-2020-2767 CVE-2020-2757 CVE-2020-2756 CVE-2020-2755 CVE-2020-2754   openjdk 11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 72</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-72/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 10:46:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-72/</guid>
      <description>Overview A huge number of CVEs fixed in the various Ubuntu releases, including for PHP, Git, Thunderbird, GNU binutils and more, plus Joe McManus discusses ROS with Sid Faber.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 93 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4330-1] PHP vulnerabilities [01:03]  5 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty ESM, Xenial, Bionic, Eoan  CVE-2020-7066 CVE-2020-7065 CVE-2020-7064 CVE-2020-7063 CVE-2020-7062   php5, php7.0, php7.2, php7.3 get_headers() would silently truncate a URL containing a NUL terminator (\0) - so if used with user-supplied URL could get wrong details from the server stack overflow in mb_strtolower() when handling UTF32-LE encoding 1 byte buffer overread in handling EXIF data - info leak / crash PHAR archives created with world readable permissions NULL pointer dereference on file upload in certain situations -&amp;gt; crash  [USN-4331-1] WebKitGTK+ vulnerability [02:32]  1 CVEs addressed in Bionic, Eoan  CVE-2020-11793   UAF when processing maliciously crafted web content  [USN-4332-1] File Roller vulnerability [02:51]  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Eoan  CVE-2020-11736   Possible directory traversal issue when extracting an archive where parent of file is a symlink pointing outside of the archive  [USN-4334-1] Git vulnerability [03:08]  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Eoan  CVE-2020-11008 Similar to CVE-2020-5260 from Episode 71 - due to an incomplete fix for that where some credentials may still be leaked but the attacker cannot control which ones    [USN-4333-1] Python vulnerabilities [03:47]  2 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty ESM, Xenial, Bionic, Eoan  CVE-2020-8492 CVE-2019-18348   CRLF injection via an attacker controlled url parameter to urlopen() function in urllib  [USN-4335-1] Thunderbird vulnerabilities [04:09]  39 CVEs addressed in Xenial  CVE-2020-6811 CVE-2020-6794 CVE-2020-6822 CVE-2020-6795 CVE-2020-6793 CVE-2020-6792 CVE-2019-15903 CVE-2019-11755 CVE-2019-11745 CVE-2020-6825 CVE-2020-6821 CVE-2020-6820 CVE-2020-6819 CVE-2020-6814 CVE-2020-6812 CVE-2020-6807 CVE-2020-6806 CVE-2020-6805 CVE-2020-6800 CVE-2020-6798 CVE-2019-20503 CVE-2019-17026 CVE-2019-17024 CVE-2019-17022 CVE-2019-17017 CVE-2019-17016 CVE-2019-17012 CVE-2019-17011 CVE-2019-17010 CVE-2019-17008 CVE-2019-17005 CVE-2019-11764 CVE-2019-11763 CVE-2019-11762 CVE-2019-11761 CVE-2019-11760 CVE-2019-11759 CVE-2019-11758 CVE-2019-11757   Updated to latest upstream version 68.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 71</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-71/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 12:57:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-71/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week Joe discusses Ubuntu&amp;rsquo;s involvement in ZDI&amp;rsquo;s Pwn2Own with special guests Steve Beattie and Marc Deslauriers from the Ubuntu Security team, plus we do the usual roundup of fixed vulnerabilities including libssh, Thunderbird, Git and a kernel Livepatch.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 38 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4325-1] Linux kernel vulnerabilities [00:59]  2 CVEs addressed in Bionic  CVE-2020-8428 CVE-2019-19046   5.0 (bionic clouds / oem - oracle, gke, gcp, azure, etc) VFS UAF and IPMI memory leak - Episode 70  [USN-4326-1] libiberty vulnerabilities [01:46]  14 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic  CVE-2019-9071 CVE-2019-9070 CVE-2019-14250 CVE-2018-9138 CVE-2018-18701 CVE-2018-18700 CVE-2018-18484 CVE-2018-18483 CVE-2018-17985 CVE-2018-17794 CVE-2018-12934 CVE-2018-12698 CVE-2018-12697 CVE-2018-12641   libib - collection of subroutines used by other libraries / applications  primarily binutils for parsing binary formats (ELF executables etc)   Mostly low priority issues (DoS via memory leak / NULL ptr dereference in say objdump etc) 1 medium - integer overflow -&amp;gt; heap buffer overflow in parsing a crafted ELF file  [USN-4327-1] libssh vulnerability [02:57]  1 CVEs addressed in Bionic, Eoan  CVE-2020-1730   Malicious client / server could crash other end when using AES-CTR ciphers - error in memory handling on cleanup of cipher context when closing the connection -&amp;gt; DoS  [LSN-0065-1] Linux kernel vulnerability [03:41]  3 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic  CVE-2020-8428 CVE-2019-3016 CVE-2013-1798   Livepatch for VFS UAF, fix a possible SpectreV1/L1TF gadget introduced back in 2013 for a KVM IOAPIC issue, KVM TLB flush (Episode 67)  [USN-4328-1] Thunderbird vulnerabilities [04:31]  18 CVEs addressed in Bionic, Eoan  CVE-2020-6811 CVE-2020-6825 CVE-2020-6821 CVE-2020-6820 CVE-2020-6819 CVE-2020-6814 CVE-2020-6812 CVE-2020-6807 CVE-2020-6806 CVE-2020-6805 CVE-2020-6800 CVE-2020-6798 CVE-2019-20503 CVE-2020-6794 CVE-2020-6822 CVE-2020-6795 CVE-2020-6793 CVE-2020-6792   68.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 70</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-70/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 14:12:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-70/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we have a great interview between Joe McManus and Emilia Torino from the Ubuntu Security team, plus we cover security updates for Apport, Firefox, GnuTLS, the Linux kernel and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 18 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4315-1] Apport vulnerabilities [00:32]  2 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Eoan  CVE-2020-8833 CVE-2020-8831   Apport creates it&amp;rsquo;s lock file as world writable in a world-writable location - so a local attacker could create a symlink in it&amp;rsquo;s place to a non-existant file in a root-owned location and Apport would end up creating that file but with world-writable permissions - so could be used to possibly escalate privileges say by dropping a new cron file or similar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 69</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-69/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 16:32:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-69/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we cover security updates for a Linux kernel vulnerability disclosed during pwn2own, Timeshift, pam-krb5 and more, plus we have a special guest, Vineetha Kamath, to discuss security certifications for Ubuntu.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 10 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4308-2] Twisted vulnerabilities [00:42]  4 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM  CVE-2020-10109 CVE-2020-10108 CVE-2019-12855 CVE-2019-12387   Episode 68 - 4 of the 7 CVEs described there affect Twisted in 14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 68</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-68/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 13:57:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-68/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we cover security updates for Apache, Twisted, Vim a kernel livepatch and more, plus Alex and Joe discuss OVAL data feeds and the cvescan snap for vulnerability awareness.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 16 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4307-1] Apache HTTP Server update [00:24]  TLSv1.3 enabled in Ubuntu 18.04 LTS (bionic)  Enabled by default, could cause compatibility issues in some environments - can be disabled using the SSLProtocol directive https://bugs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 67</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-67/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 20:25:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-67/</guid>
      <description>Overview A big week in security updates, including the Linux kernel, Ceph, ICU, Firefox, Dino and more, plus Joe and Alex discuss tips for securely working from home in light of Coronavirus.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 38 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4299-1] Firefox vulnerabilities [00:41]  12 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Eoan  CVE-2020-6811 CVE-2020-6809 CVE-2020-6815 CVE-2020-6814 CVE-2020-6813 CVE-2020-6812 CVE-2020-6810 CVE-2020-6808 CVE-2020-6807 CVE-2020-6806 CVE-2020-6805 CVE-2019-20503   74.0 - usual sorts of fixes:  Crafted website -&amp;gt; DoS, URL and other browser chrome spoofing, bypass content security policy protections, RCE etc Extensions with all-url permission could access local files Copy-as-cURL devtools feature failed to escape website-controlled data - possible command injection -&amp;gt; RCE if user tricked into using this on a crafted website    [USN-4300-1] Linux kernel vulnerabilities [02:02]  11 CVEs addressed in Bionic, Eoan  CVE-2019-19068 CVE-2019-19066 CVE-2019-19064 CVE-2019-19059 CVE-2019-19058 CVE-2019-19056 CVE-2019-19053 CVE-2019-19043 CVE-2019-18809 CVE-2020-2732 CVE-2019-3016   5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 66</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-66/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 22:39:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-66/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we cover security updates for Django, runC and SQLite, plus Alex and Joe discuss the AMD speculative execution Take A Way attack and we look at some recent blog posts by the team too.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 16 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4296-1] Django vulnerability [00:49]  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Eoan  CVE-2020-9402   Possible SQL injection in the GIS functions when using an Oracle DB as the backend - Oracle provides a tolerance parameter which can be used when doing GIS queries and this was not properly sanitised before use so could allow SQL injection  [USN-4297-1] runC vulnerabilities [01:30]  2 CVEs addressed in Bionic, Eoan  CVE-2019-19921 CVE-2019-16884   Race condition on mounting of shared volume mounts between two containers - can replace /proc on one container with a symlink inside of the shared mount - when this gets cleaned up other parts of /proc can end mounted within the shared mount and this could be used for privilege escalation since if outside of /proc then regular users might be able to write to sensitive parts of /proc - fixed by having runc validate that the target for mounting /proc or /sys must either not exist or must be a directory to avoid symlink attacks etc Possible bypass of AppArmor restrictions since would not properly check the target of a mount and so could end up mounting a malicious image over /proc - instead add more explicit checks on whether the dest of a mount is /proc and only allow this if the source is also a procfs  [USN-4298-1] SQLite vulnerabilities [03:09]  13 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Eoan  CVE-2019-13752 CVE-2020-9327 CVE-2019-20218 CVE-2019-19926 CVE-2019-19959 CVE-2019-19925 CVE-2019-19924 CVE-2019-19923 CVE-2019-19880 CVE-2019-13751 CVE-2019-13753 CVE-2019-13750 CVE-2019-13734   Many different memory safety issues resolved in SQLite - across various parts of SQLite including handling of shadow tables, corrupt records, parsing, ZIP archives and column optimisations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 65</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-65/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 14:35:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-65/</guid>
      <description>Overview Whilst avoiding Coronavirus, this week we look at updates for libarchive, OpenSMTPD, rake and more, plus Joe and Alex discuss ROS, the Robot Operating System and how the Ubuntu Security Team is involved in the ongoing development of secure foundations for robotics.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 7 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4293-1] libarchive vulnerabilities [00:18]  2 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Eoan  CVE-2020-9308 CVE-2019-19221   OSS-Fuzz: RAR unpacker would try and unpack a file with a corrupted / malformed header (ie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 64</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-64/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 22:01:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-64/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at security updates for ppp, Squid, rsync + more, and Joe and Alex discuss the wide scope of the Ubuntu Security Team including some current open positions.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 19 unique CVEs addressed
[LSN-0063-1] Linux kernel vulnerability [00:43]  5 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic  CVE-2020-7053 CVE-2019-20096 CVE-2019-19050 CVE-2019-14615 CVE-2019-5108   i915 UAF (Episode 60), DCCP memory leak -&amp;gt; DoS (Episode 63), crypto subsystem memory leaks (Episode 60), i915 info leak (Episode 60, Episode 53), WiFi AP mode DoS (Episode 53)  [USN-4279-2] PHP regression [01:51]  3 CVEs addressed in Xenial  CVE-2020-7060 CVE-2020-7059 CVE-2015-9253   Episode 63 - Upstream fix for CVE-2015-9253 contained a memory leak - this fix was backed-out in this update  [USN-4288-1] ppp vulnerability [02:16]  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Eoan  CVE-2020-8597   Included a check for possible buffer overflow a an rhostname but the check was incorrect :( so could still overflow - fixed by making the correct check  [USN-4289-1] Squid vulnerabilities [02:41]  4 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Eoan  CVE-2020-8517 CVE-2020-8450 CVE-2020-8449 CVE-2019-12528   Buffer overflow in NTLM credentials parser - out-of-process so would just result in a DoS Buffer overflow when acting as a reverse proxy Incorrect input validation leading to access to server resources which should have been prohibited Info disclosure due to heap buffer over-read when acting as an FTP client from a malicious FTP server  [USN-4290-1] libpam-radius-auth vulnerability [03:26]  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Eoan  CVE-2015-9542   Stack overflow in password field handling -&amp;gt; crash, DoS  [USN-4291-1] mod-auth-mellon vulnerability [03:49]  1 CVEs addressed in Bionic, Eoan  CVE-2019-13038   SAML 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 63</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-63/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 15:51:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-63/</guid>
      <description>Overview Security updates for Firefox, QEMU, Linux kernel, ClamAV and more, plus we discuss our recommended reading list for getting into infosec and farewell long-time member of the Ubuntu Security Team / community Tyler Hicks.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 54 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4278-1] Firefox vulnerabilities [00:55]  4 CVEs addressed in Bionic, Eoan  CVE-2020-6801 CVE-2020-6800 CVE-2020-6798 CVE-2020-6796   Firefox 73.0  Various memory safety issues Possible XSS if a site used a tag within a tag since could allow subsequent JavaScript parsing and execution    [USN-4279-1] PHP vulnerabilities [01:26]  3 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty ESM, Xenial, Bionic, Eoan  CVE-2020-7060 CVE-2020-7059 CVE-2015-9253   Buffer overread when converting multibyte characters via mbstring functions and when reading data whilst stripping tags via fgetss() - crash / info disc Fix for a CPU and disk-based DoS when PHP FPM (FastCGI Process Manager) would endlessly restart a child process - busy CPU loop and large error logs -&amp;gt; DoS  [USN-4280-1, USN-4280-2] ClamAV vulnerability [02:27]  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty ESM, Xenial, Bionic, Eoan  CVE-2020-3123   OOB read in Data-Loss-Prevention (DLP) module (scans for CC or social security numbers) - crafted email would cause OOB read -&amp;gt; crash -&amp;gt; DoS  [USN-4281-1] WebKitGTK+ vulnerabilities [03:04]  5 CVEs addressed in Bionic, Eoan  CVE-2020-3868 CVE-2020-3867 CVE-2020-3865 CVE-2020-3864 CVE-2020-3862   Various issues able to be triggered by malicious websites  DoS via poor memory handling Wrong secrity origin for particular DOM objects Top-level DOM object incorrectly considered secure Logic issue leading to a universal XSS flaw Poor memory handling leading to RCE    [USN-4282-1] PostgreSQL vulnerability [03:50]  1 CVEs addressed in Bionic, Eoan  CVE-2020-1720   Missing authorization checks on ALTER &amp;hellip; DEPENDS ON EXTENSION sub-commands - could allow unprivileged users to drop any function, procedure, index etc under certain conditions  [USN-4283-1] QEMU vulnerabilities [04:10]  3 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Eoan  CVE-2020-8608 CVE-2020-7039 CVE-2020-1711   Buffer overflow in libslirp tcp emulation due to misuse of snprintf() return value - assumed snprintf() returns the number of bytes written - BUT returns the number of bytes which would have been written if the dest buffer was big enough - so if buffer is too small then returns a value larger than the buffer - so if that returned size is used later in a memcpy() or similar would overflow the buffer - so instead need to carefully track the return value if it is larger than the dest buffer Separate buffer overflow in libslirp tcp emulation code due to missing size checks Heap buffer OOB write in iSCSI block driver - malicious iSCSI server could trigger this and crash or possibly get code execution on QEMU host  [USN-4284-1] Linux kernel vulnerabilities [05:21]  23 CVEs addressed in Bionic, Eoan  CVE-2019-15291 CVE-2019-19965 CVE-2019-19947 CVE-2019-19767 CVE-2019-19602 CVE-2019-19332 CVE-2019-19252 CVE-2019-19241 CVE-2019-19082 CVE-2019-19078 CVE-2019-19077 CVE-2019-19071 CVE-2019-19063 CVE-2019-19057 CVE-2019-19062 CVE-2019-19050 CVE-2019-18811 CVE-2019-18786 CVE-2019-18683 CVE-2019-16232 CVE-2019-16229 CVE-2019-15099 CVE-2019-14615   5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 62</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-62/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 21:53:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-62/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week Alex and Joe take an indepth look at the recent Sudo vulnerability CVE-2019-18634 plus we look at security updates for OpenSMTPD, systemd, Mesa, Yubico PIV tool and more. We also look at a recent job opening for a Robotics Security Engineer to join the Ubuntu Security team.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 33 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4263-2] Sudo vulnerability [00:41]  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty ESM  CVE-2019-18634   See Episode 61 and discussion later in episode  [USN-4268-1] OpenSMTPD vulnerability [01:02]  1 CVEs addressed in Bionic, Eoan  CVE-2020-7247   Logic bug caused existing sanity checks on MAIL FROM field to be skipped under certain scenarios - so by failing to perform this validation, could allow an attacker to input shell metacharacters to obtain command execution in smtpd (which runs as root) -&amp;gt; remote root command execution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 61</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-61/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 16:15:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-61/</guid>
      <description>Overview Joe is back to discuss a recent breach against Wawa, plus we detail security updates from the past week including Apache Solr, OpenStack Keystone, Sudo, Django and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 23 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4259-1] Apache Solr vulnerability [00:50]  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial  CVE-2017-12629   Enterprise search server based on Lucene with XML/HTTP and JSON APIs Was vulnerable to an XML External Entity (XXE) attack - XML can include a reference to another XML resource which might then be fetched - this could then be combined with another flaw (use of Config API to obtain access to the RunExecutableListener class) to allow remote code fetched from the remote XML  [USN-4261-1] WebKitGTK+ vulnerabilities [01:44]  3 CVEs addressed in Bionic, Eoan  CVE-2019-8846 CVE-2019-8844 CVE-2019-8835   Various memory management issues which could be triggered via a malicious websites - possible remote code execution as a result  [USN-4262-1] OpenStack Keystone vulnerability [02:13]  1 CVEs addressed in Eoan  CVE-2019-19687   Keystone provides identity services (client authentication etc) for OpenStack credentials API allowed any user with a role on a project to list all credentials when enforce_scope was false - so could view other users credentials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 60</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-60/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 17:12:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-60/</guid>
      <description>Overview Security updates for python-apt, GnuTLS, tcpdump, the Linux kernel and more, plus we look at plans to integrate Ubuntu Security Notices within the main ubuntu.com website.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 91 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4247-1, USN-4247-2, USN-4247-3] python-apt vulnerabilities [00:42]  2 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty ESM, Xenial, Bionic, Disco, Eoan  CVE-2019-15796 CVE-2019-15795   Could still use md5 to validate downloads - md5 has been broken for a while now so if md5 hashes were available for a repo then these would be trusted - instead, verify all hashes Ensure repository is trusted before downloading from it - in some cases, could configure repositories that were not trusted and python-apt based clients would not check trust - so would use it - now always check and verify unless the repository is specifically configured as trusted  [USN-4248-1] GraphicsMagick vulnerabilities [02:31]  10 CVEs addressed in Xenial  CVE-2017-17783 CVE-2017-17782 CVE-2017-17503 CVE-2017-17502 CVE-2017-17501 CVE-2017-17500 CVE-2017-17498 CVE-2017-16669 CVE-2017-16547 CVE-2017-16545   Episode 59, Episode 57, Episode 55 etc  [USN-4246-1] zlib vulnerabilities [02:55]  4 CVEs addressed in Xenial  CVE-2016-9843 CVE-2016-9842 CVE-2016-9841 CVE-2016-9840   Trail of Bits security audit of zlib found various instances of undefined behaviour in the implementation - pointer increment operations on undefined memory ranges, shifts by negative indices etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 59</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-59/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 08:57:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-59/</guid>
      <description>Overview After a weeks break we are back to look at updates for ClamAV, GnuTLS, nginx, Samba and more, plus we briefly discuss the current 20.04 Mid-Cycle Roadmap Review sprint for the Ubuntu Security Team
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 73 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4230-1] ClamAV vulnerability [01:16]  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Disco, Eoan  CVE-2019-15961   Backport latest upstream release (0.102.1) from focal CPU based DoS when scanning crafted emails - parsing of MIME components in particular  [USN-4232-1] GraphicsMagick vulnerabilities [01:52]  11 CVEs addressed in Xenial  CVE-2017-16353 CVE-2017-16352 CVE-2017-15930 CVE-2017-15277 CVE-2017-14997 CVE-2017-14994 CVE-2017-14733 CVE-2017-14649 CVE-2017-14504 CVE-2017-14314 CVE-2017-14165   Episode 57, Episode 55 Heap based buffer over-reads - info leak or crash -&amp;gt; DoS Heap based buffer over-flow - crash -&amp;gt; DoS, RCE NULL ptr derefs - crash -&amp;gt; DoS Memory overallocation -&amp;gt; memory based remote DoS  [USN-4231-1] NSS vulnerability [03:04]  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty ESM, Xenial, Bionic, Disco, Eoan  CVE-2019-17006   UBSAN found possible buffer overflow due to failure to check lengths of inputs to various functions - so applications using libnss for crypto could be vulnerable to buffer overflow  [USN-4233-1] GnuTLS update [03:54]  Affecting Xenial, Bionic Update marks SHA1 as being untrusted for digital signature operations - SHA1 has been broken in theory for a while and 2017 Google showed the first SHA1 collision - recently the first chosen-prefix attack was demonstrated against SHA1 as well - demonstrated by creating a GPG key which can impersonate another As such GnuTLS will not trust SHA1 based digital signatures since these can relatively easily be forged now (but not for an arbitrary input) As such libraries / applications which use GnuTLS (libsoup, Epiphany) will not trust SHA1 based digital signatures https://sha-mbles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 58</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-58/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 16:18:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-58/</guid>
      <description>Overview In the first episode for 2020, we look at security updates for Django and the Linux kernel, plus Alex and Joe discuss security and privacy aspects of smart assistant connected devices.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 34 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4224-1] Django vulnerability [00:51]  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Disco, Eoan  CVE-2019-19844   Account takeover via password reset - when comparing email addresses, would not do a proper unicode comparison - and so could specify an email address which appears equal to an existing users email address (after unicode case and character transmformation) and would then get sent a token to reset their accounts password to your doppleganger email address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 57</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-57/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 13:36:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-57/</guid>
      <description>Overview In the final episode of 2019, we look at security updates for RabbitMQ, GraphicsMagick, OpenJDK and more, plus Joe and Alex discuss a typical day-in-the-life of a Ubuntu Security Team member.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 34 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4217-2] Samba vulnerabilities [01:00]  2 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM  CVE-2019-14870 CVE-2019-14861   See Episode 56  [USN-4214-2] RabbitMQ vulnerability [01:23]  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic  CVE-2019-18609   AMQP implementation Possible integer overflow when handling the CONNECTION_STATE_HEADER frame - rogue server could return a malicious frame header which is then processed by the client and leads to a smaller target_size value due to integer overflow - then when the frame data is copied in via memcpy() this would overwrite past the bounds of the heap allocation, and with attacker controlled data Not an issue if connecting to trusted servers  [USN-4222-1] GraphicsMagick vulnerabilities [02:28]  15 CVEs addressed in Xenial  CVE-2017-13777 CVE-2017-13776 CVE-2017-13775 CVE-2017-13737 CVE-2017-13134 CVE-2017-13065 CVE-2017-13064 CVE-2017-13063 CVE-2017-12937 CVE-2017-12936 CVE-2017-12935 CVE-2017-11643 CVE-2017-11642 CVE-2017-11641 CVE-2017-11638   Episode 55 covered previous update for GraphicsMagick - more of the same here  [USN-4223-1] OpenJDK vulnerabilities [03:00]  16 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Disco, Eoan  CVE-2019-2999 CVE-2019-2992 CVE-2019-2989 CVE-2019-2988 CVE-2019-2987 CVE-2019-2983 CVE-2019-2978 CVE-2019-2977 CVE-2019-2975 CVE-2019-2981 CVE-2019-2973 CVE-2019-2964 CVE-2019-2962 CVE-2019-2949 CVE-2019-2945 CVE-2019-2894   Latest upstream micro-release for openjdk 8 and openjdk 11 Various mix of issues (buffer overflows, NULL pointer dereferences and various denial of service issues on application crashes in different scenarios) - see the full USN for details  Goings on in Ubuntu Security Community Joe and Alex discuss a day-in-the-life of a Ubuntu Security Team member [03:50] Get in contact  security@ubuntu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 56</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-56/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 20:49:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-56/</guid>
      <description>Overview In the second to last episode for 2019, we look at security updates for Samba, Squid, Git, HAProxy and more, plus Alex and Joe discuss Evil Corp hacker indictments, unsecured AWS S3 buckets and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 43 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4212-1] HAProxy vulnerability [00:50]  1 CVEs addressed in Bionic, Disco, Eoan  CVE-2019-19330   Failed to treat malformed headers as invalid - HTTP/2 allows encoding headers as binary and these can then contain characters which would be invalid when converted to HTTP/1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 55</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-55/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 13:05:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-55/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we cover security updates for NSS, SQLite, the Linux kernel and more, plus Joe and Alex discuss a recent FBI advisory warning about possible dangers of Smart TVs.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 49 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4203-1, USN-4203-2] NSS vulnerability [00:59]  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty ESM, Xenial, Bionic, Disco, Eoan  CVE-2019-11745   OOB write if using an output buffer smaller than the block size (since used block size instead of buffer size) when writing output for NSC_EncryptUpdate()  [USN-4204-1] psutil vulnerability [02:05]  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Disco, Eoan  CVE-2019-18874   Double free due to mishandling of reference counting when handling errors during conversion of system data into Python objects - could be triggered when using a malicious disk partition label with an invalid character that fails to decode - so triggers error than fails to cleanup properly and results in a double free  [USN-4205-1] SQLite vulnerabilities [02:59]  6 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Xenial, Bionic, Disco, Eoan  CVE-2019-5827 CVE-2019-5018 CVE-2019-19244 CVE-2019-19242 CVE-2019-16168 CVE-2018-8740   Various robustness updates for SQLite related to CVEs from other applications that misuse SQLite - so this makes SQLite more tolerant if it is misused in the future - plus a fix of a possible crash (DoS) under certain usage scenarios.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 54</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-54/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2019 10:16:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-54/</guid>
      <description>Overview Security updates for DPDK, Linux kernel, QEMU, ImageMagick, Ghostscript and more, plus Joe and Alex talk about how to get into information security.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 89 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4189-1] DPDK vulnerability [01:00]  1 CVEs addressed in Bionic, Disco, Eoan  CVE-2019-14818   Data Plane Development Kit - Memory and file-descriptor leak, able to be triggered by a malicious master or a container with access to the vhost_user socket  [USN-4190-1] libjpeg-turbo vulnerabilities [01:41]  4 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Disco  CVE-2019-2201 CVE-2018-20330 CVE-2018-19664 CVE-2018-14498   2 x heap-buffer overflow - crash or possible RCE 2 x heap-buffer overread - crash  [USN-4183-2] Linux kernel vulnerability [02:48]  9 CVEs addressed in Eoan  CVE-2019-17666 CVE-2019-16746 CVE-2019-15793 CVE-2019-15792 CVE-2019-15791 CVE-2019-0154 CVE-2018-12207 CVE-2019-11135 CVE-2019-0155   Episode 53 - Extra update for CVE-2019-0155 (i915 blitter command streamer) - previous one was based on an in-flight patch that got changed at the last minute before the CRD - part of this fix is to whitelist certain commands to the command-streamer, and this is done via a bitmask - this used a memset() to zero it out but assumed the size of the underlying data was 32-bit - so on 64-bit platforms this becomes a 64-bit size and so half the bitmask is not zeroed out - meaning the whitelist may be able to be bypassed - this fix includes the final upstream fix  [USN-4184-2] Linux kernel vulnerability and regression [04:37]  14 CVEs addressed in Bionic (HWE), Disco  CVE-2019-17666 CVE-2019-17056 CVE-2019-17055 CVE-2019-17054 CVE-2019-17053 CVE-2019-17052 CVE-2019-15793 CVE-2019-15792 CVE-2019-15791 CVE-2019-15098 CVE-2019-0154 CVE-2018-12207 CVE-2019-11135 CVE-2019-0155   See above (i915 vuln) - but also includes a fix for a regression that was introduced in last week&amp;rsquo;s kernel - KVM guests would fail to launch if extended page tables were disabled or not supported.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 53</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-53/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 18:21:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-53/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at the details of the latest Intel hardware vulnerabilities, including security updates for the Linux kernel and Intel microcode, plus Bash, cpio, FriBidi and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 26 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4176-1] GNU cpio vulnerability [01:00]  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty ESM, Xenial, Bionic, Disco, Eoan  CVE-2019-14866   cpio wouldn&amp;rsquo;t validate values written to headers of TAR archives - could use cpio to create a TAR containing another TAR with a big size and will use wrong context values (ie uses inner TAR values in header) - this could allow a TAR to be created which has files with permissions not owned by the original user - when extracted by cpio will overwrite target files - whereas if using tar to extract will avoid this - fixed to check and handle header values correctly  [USN-4177-1] Rygel vulnerability [02:18]  Affecting Eoan Added Rygel in Eoan which is off by default but needed GNOME to handle that - it would disable it dynamically - so if not running GNOME, rygel would be running and sharing your stuff on the local network - fixed to disable automatically on upgrade - and then can use the GNOME settings front-end etc to re-enable if desired  [USN-4178-1] WebKitGTK+ vulnerabilities [03:34]  4 CVEs addressed in Bionic, Disco  CVE-2019-8771 CVE-2019-8769 CVE-2019-8720 CVE-2019-8625    [USN-4181-1] WebKitGTK+ vulnerabilities [03:34]  2 CVEs addressed in Bionic, Disco, Eoan  CVE-2019-8814 CVE-2019-8812    [USN-4179-1] FriBidi vulnerability [04:00]  1 CVEs addressed in Disco, Eoan  CVE-2019-18397   Issue reported about unicode isolated handling in Qt - turns out affected GTK applications as well - entirely different code with very similar flaw - stack buffer overflow since didn&amp;rsquo;t check bounds of a fixed array used to store details on nested unicode isolate sections - simple fix to just check bounds before trying to store next element  [USN-4180-1] Bash vulnerability [05:38]  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM  CVE-2012-6711   Recently announced vuln (heap-based buffer overflow) in bash affecting old versions - so most releases unaffected except Precise - can trigger by printing wide characters via echo -e  [USN-4182-1, USN-4182-2] Intel Microcode update [06:12]  2 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM, Xenial, Bionic, Disco, Eoan  CVE-2019-11139 CVE-2019-11135   Voltage modulation able to be performed by a local privileged user - disabled via microcode TSX Asynchronous Abort (TAA) - https://wiki.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 52</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-52/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 21:48:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-52/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at security updates for FreeTDS, HAProxy, Nokogiri, plus some regressions in Whoopsie, Apport and Firefox, and Joe and Alex discuss the release of 14.04 ESM for personal use under the Ubuntu Advantage program.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 9 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4171-2] Apport vulnerabilities [00:44]  5 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM  CVE-2019-15790 CVE-2019-11485 CVE-2019-11483 CVE-2019-11482 CVE-2019-11481   Episode 51  [USN-4172-1, USN-4172-2] file vulnerability [00:58]  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty ESM, Xenial, Bionic, Disco, Eoan  CVE-2019-18218   OSS-Fuzz using libFuzzer - heap based buffer overflow of up to 4 bytes in the CDF parser when handing vector elements - Composite Document File - used in MS Office prior to new zipped XML format - ie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 51</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-51/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 18:00:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-51/</guid>
      <description>Overview In this Halloween Special, Joe and Alex talk about what scares them in security, plus we look at security updates for Firefox, PHP, Samba, Whoopsie, Apport and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 26 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4165-1] Firefox vulnerabilities [00:46]  13 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Disco, Eoan  CVE-2019-17002 CVE-2019-17001 CVE-2019-17000 CVE-2019-15903 CVE-2019-11765 CVE-2019-11764 CVE-2019-11763 CVE-2019-11762 CVE-2019-11761 CVE-2019-11760 CVE-2019-11759 CVE-2019-11757 CVE-2018-6156   1 high priority, 11 medium and 1 low  Heap buffer overflow via a crafted WebRTC video - originally for Chromium and was fixed for that last year - Firefox suffered similarly but disables the feature by default - has finally been fixed for Firefox as well by integrating the original fix from Chromium Usual suspects of stack-based buffer overflows, UAFs, a heap buffer overflow in bundled expat (Episode 47),    [USN-4166-1, USN-4166-2] PHP vulnerability [02:10]  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty ESM, Xenial, Bionic, Disco, Eoan  CVE-2019-11043   RCE in PHP (FPM - FastCGI Process Manager) - possible to cause the FPM module to write past allocated buffers - and so ends up also writing into the FCGI protocol data buffers - which can then create a chance for RCE Exploit on github targetting vulnerable PHP-FPM servers which use nginx in a particular configuration  [USN-4167-1, USN-4167-2] Samba vulnerabilities [03:11]  3 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty ESM, Xenial, Bionic, Disco, Eoan  CVE-2019-14847 CVE-2019-14833 CVE-2019-10218   DoS from a user with &amp;ldquo;get changes&amp;rdquo; permissions - could crash an AD DC LDAP server due to a NULL pointer deref when using dirsync with ranged results Can configure AD DC to call out to a custom command to verify password complexity - is handed a copy of the cleartext password - but if this contained any multi-byte characters, would not get the full password - since it would pass the password as bytes but only copy the number of characters - and since multi-byte characters take more than 1 byte would miss the last few bytes of the password - so could circumvent password complexity requirements Malicious server could craft filenames which contain relative path characters (.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 50</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-50/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 15:28:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-50/</guid>
      <description>Overview Alex and Joe discuss the big news of this week - the release of Ubuntu 19.10 Eoan Ermine - plus we look at updates for the Linux kernel, libxslt, UW IMAP and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 51 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4156-2] SDL vulnerabilities [00:37]  11 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty ESM  CVE-2019-7637 CVE-2019-7636 CVE-2019-7635 CVE-2019-7578 CVE-2019-7577 CVE-2019-7576 CVE-2019-7575 CVE-2019-7574 CVE-2019-7573 CVE-2019-7572 CVE-2019-13616   Covered in Episode 49 and Episode 48  [USN-4160-1] UW IMAP vulnerability [01:04]  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Disco  CVE-2018-19518   University of Washington IMAP toolkit (used by PHP for it&amp;rsquo;s IMAP implementation) Used rsh to implement various operations - wouldn&amp;rsquo;t try and sanitize the provided hostname - so if attacker could provide a hostname/mailbox to php&amp;rsquo;s IMAP without any validation could execute arbitrary commands on the host  Fixed by turning off the rsh based functionality by default in PHP - if you still want this you can set imap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 49</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-49/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 14:18:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-49/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at updates for Sudo, Python, OpenStack Octavia and more, plus we discuss a recent CVE for Python which resulted in erroneous scientific research results, and we go over some of your feedback from Episode 48.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 27 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4148-1] OpenEXR vulnerabilities [00:45]  8 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Disco  CVE-2018-18444 CVE-2017-9115 CVE-2017-9113 CVE-2017-9111 CVE-2017-9116 CVE-2017-9112 CVE-2017-9110 CVE-2017-12596   Image format developed by ILM with a high definition range for computer imaging applications Range of issues (c++ codebase)  OOB writes (usually only of a few bytes past the end of a buffer) - assertion failure or memory corruption -&amp;gt; crash / code execution OOB reads (same) - crash    [USN-4149-1] Unbound vulnerability [02:06]  1 CVEs addressed in Disco  CVE-2019-16866   Validating, recursive DNS resolver OOB read due to a remotely crafted NOTIFY query (source IP needs to match an ACL) -&amp;gt; crash  [USN-4151-1, USN-4151-2] Python vulnerabilities [02:40]  2 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty ESM, Xenial, Bionic, Disco  CVE-2019-16935 CVE-2019-16056   XML-RPC server module could end up serving arbitrary JS if set via the set_server_title() method as did not escape content Python email module tries to parse email address into sender + domain - if domain contains multiple @ chars could get confused and return wrong output - so applications which rely on this for validating email addresses could accept an email address which is actually invalid  [USN-4152-1] libsoup vulnerability [03:53]  1 CVEs addressed in Bionic, Disco  CVE-2019-17266   Heap buffer OOB read - fails to check the specified length of message against the actual received message - could then memcpy past the end of the input message -&amp;gt; crash  [USN-4153-1] Octavia vulnerability [04:33]  1 CVEs addressed in Disco  CVE-2019-17134   Amphora Images in OpenStack Octavia - fails to properly validate client certificates for management network clients -&amp;gt; could allow anyone with management network access to retrieve information / issue config commands  [USN-4154-1] Sudo vulnerability [05:06]  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty ESM, Xenial, Bionic, Disco  CVE-2019-14287   Lots of press around a seemingly high priority privilege escalation vulnerability - BUT requires an admin to have configured sudo with a particular configuration (ie specifying a user can run a command as any other user via the ALL keyword in a Runas rule).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 48</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-48/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 20:37:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-48/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at security updates for the Linux kernel, SDL 2, ClamAV and more, plus Alex and Joe talk security and performance trade-offs, snaps and OWASP Top 10 Cloud Security recommendations, and finally Alex covers some recent concerns about the security of the Snap Store.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 31 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4142-1, USN-4142-2] e2fsprogs vulnerability [00:37]  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty ESM, Xenial, Bionic, Disco  CVE-2019-5094   Cisco TALOS - possible code execution via OOB write to the heap for code which handles quota support in ext4 - so possible to trigger via a specially crafted ext4 partition - could be triggered during an fsck on the partition etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 47</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-47/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 20:22:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-47/</guid>
      <description>Overview We catch up on details of the past few weeks of security updates, including Python, curl, Linux kernel, Exim and more, plus Alex and Joe discuss the recent Ubuntu Engineering Sprint in Paris and building a HoneyBot for Admin Magazine.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 93 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4125-1] Memcached vulnerability [00:42]  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Disco  CVE-2019-15026   Possible stack buffer over-read when using UNIX sockets (copies address of UNIX socket using strncpy() which could possibly read past the end of the src buffer) - possible crash -&amp;gt; DoS - fixed to explicitly limit length to smallest of src/dst buffers rather than just size of dest buffer  [USN-4126-1] FreeType vulnerability [01:49]  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty ESM, Xenial  CVE-2015-9383   2 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty ESM only  CVE-2015-9382 CVE-2015-9381   All various heap based buffer over-reads - crash -&amp;gt; DoS  [USN-4127-1, USN-4127-2] Python vulnerabilities [02:13]  8 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty ESM, Xenial, Bionic, Disco  CVE-2019-9948 CVE-2019-9947 CVE-2019-9740 CVE-2019-5010 CVE-2019-10160 CVE-2019-9636 CVE-2018-20852 CVE-2018-20406   4 issues in urllib:  would allow to easily open files from local file-system 2 different CRLF injection issues specially crafted URL could cause urllib to send cookies / auth data for wrong host  Fixed incorrectly upstream so had a two CVEs assigned     http cookiejar wouldn&amp;rsquo;t validate URL correctly so could also send cookies for another domain Possible NULL ptr deref when parsing X509 certs if had an empty CRL distpoint / URI Possible integer overflow when serializing a tens of hundreds of gigabytes of data via the pickle format - could cause memory exhaustion  [USN-4128-1, USN-4128-2] Tomcat vulnerabilities [03:35]  3 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic (tomcat-8) and Bionic, Disco (tomcat-9)  CVE-2019-10072 CVE-2019-0199 CVE-2019-0221   HTTP/2 server would accept streams with an excessive number of SETTINGS frames and would permit clients to keep streams open without reading / writing anything - could lead to DoS by causing server-side threads to block  Original fix was incomplete - so got a second CVE   Possible XSS injection if using SSI printenv command as would echo user provided data without escaping - intended only for debugging so shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be used in a production website anyway  [USN-4120-2] systemd regression [04:45]  Affecting Bionic, Disco Episode 46 - systemd-resolved dbus access control - the update was prepared using a pending SRU update - but this contained a regression in networking - re-released the security fix but without this SRU update included.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 46</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-46/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 23:02:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-46/</guid>
      <description>Overview A massive 85 CVEs addressed this week, including updates for Exim, the Linux Kernel, Samba, systemd and more, plus we discuss hacking BMCs via remote USB devices and password stashes.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 85 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4124-1] Exim vulnerability [00:49]  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Disco  CVE-2019-15846  When doing TLS negotiation, parses the Server Name Indication headers - would try and handle escape sequences in this string.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 45</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 21:25:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-45/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at security updates for Dovecot, Ghostscript, a livepatch update for the Linux kernel, Ceph and Apache, plus Alex and Joe discuss recent Wordpress plugin vulnerabilities and the Hostinger breach, and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 22 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4110-1, USN-4110-2] Dovecot vulnerability [00:52]  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty ESM, Xenial, Bionic, Disco  CVE-2019-11500   IMAP and ManageSieve protocol parsers would not check for embedded NUL bytes in strings  When parsing these strings, would return indexes outside the normal string bounds as the first character which needed unescaping Would then go and try to unescape the string from this index, which rewrites the string on the fly, and so would then go and rewrite outside the bounds of the string Fixed to disallow embedded NUL bytes AND to not try and skip up to first unescaped character but instead loop over the whole string in unescaping    [USN-4110-3, USN-4110-4] Dovecot regression [02:08]  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty ESM, Xenial, Bionic, Disco  CVE-2019-11500   Original patch used pre-release version of the fix from upstream which contained an error such that the checking of NUL bytes was skipped - re-released with correct final upstream fix  [LSN-0054-1] Linux kernel vulnerability [02:38]  9 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic  CVE-2018-1129 CVE-2019-13272 CVE-2019-12984 CVE-2019-12819 CVE-2019-12818 CVE-2019-12614 CVE-2019-10126 CVE-2019-3846 CVE-2019-2101   Livepatch for CVEs addressed in regular kernel updates (Episode 43)  ptrace credentials race, Marvell Wifi heap-buffer overflows, NULL pointer dereferences    [USN-4111-1] Ghostscript vulnerabilities [03:20]  4 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Disco  CVE-2019-14817 CVE-2019-14813 CVE-2019-14812 CVE-2019-14811   Four more -dSAFER sandbox bypasses (see Episode 43 for the last one) All variations on the theme of using the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 44</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-44/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 20:35:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-44/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week Joe and Alex discuss a recently disclosed backdoor in Webmin, plus we cover security updates from the past week, including for Nova, KDE, LibreOffice, Docker, CUPS and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 21 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4100-1] KConfig and KDE libraries vulnerabilities [00:46]  2 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Disco  CVE-2016-6232 CVE-2019-14744   Directory traversal in KArchive via ../ RCE via malicious .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 43</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-43/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 20:58:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-43/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we cover vulnerabilities in Ghostscript, the Linux kernel, nginx and more, and we follow up last weeks interview with another interview with Jamie Strandboge, this time talking about the history of the Ubuntu Security team.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 53 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4091-1] poppler vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Bionic, Disco  CVE-2019-14494   Divide by zero when texture surface specified with 0 length or width - found via fuzzing - handled by checking first for zero-length and returning an error -&amp;gt; DoS  [USN-4092-1] Ghostscript vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Disco  CVE-2019-10216   Yet another Ghostscript -dSAFER sandbox bypass - Episode 31, Episode 25, Episode 18, Episode 14, Episode 10, Episode 7, Episode 5 Allows to escape the sandbox and use the various Ghostscript APIs for arbitrary file access / modification etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 42</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-42/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 21:13:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-42/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we have a special interview with Ubuntu Security Team member Jamie Strandboge, talking about security aspects of the Snap packaging system, as well as the usual roundup of security fixes from the past week.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 7 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4058-2] Bash vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty ESM  CVE-2019-9924   Episode 40 (rbash, BASH_CMDS)  [USN-4049-3, USN-4049-4] GLib regression  Affecting Precise ESM, Trusty ESM, Xenial Episode 40 - previous update introduced a memory leak due to backport using different API which didn&amp;rsquo;t just return a const string but allocated it and returned it but was not freed  https://bugs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 41</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-41/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 20:15:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-41/</guid>
      <description>Overview With Alex and Joe having been away at a Canonical sprint last week, we look back at the past fortnight&amp;rsquo;s security updates including new Linux kernel releases, MySQL, VLC, Django and more plus we discuss a recent Citrix password spraying attack.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 90 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4066-2] ClamAV vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty ESM  CVE-2019-1010305   Episode 40 - libmspack buffer overflow - ClamAV contains own copy of libmspack in older releases so is affected  [USN-4065-2] Squid vulnerabilities  2 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM  CVE-2019-12529 CVE-2019-12525    Episode 40 (memory corruption issues)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 40</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-40/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 09:27:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-40/</guid>
      <description>Overview Big roundup of security updates from the past 2 weeks including Docker, ZeroMQ, Squid, Redis and more, plus we talk with Joe McManus about some recent big fines for companies breaching their GDPR responsibilities and it&amp;rsquo;s EOL for Ubuntu 18.10 Cosmic Cuttlefish.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 62 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4047-1] libvirt vulnerabilities  4 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic, Disco  CVE-2019-10168 CVE-2019-10167 CVE-2019-10166 CVE-2019-10161   All related - in each case various libvirt APIs were accessible to users with read-only permissions and allowed them to perform operations which they should not have access to - in one case providing an ability to escalate privileges to root on the host - since would allow to execute arbitrary binaries with elevated permissions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 39</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-39/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 14:52:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-39/</guid>
      <description>Overview A look at security updates for Django, Thunderbird, ZNC, Irssi and more, plus news on the CanonicalLtd GitHub account credentials compromise, SKS PGP keyservers under attack and Ubuntu 18.10 Cosmic Cuttlefish reaches EOL.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 7 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4043-1] Django vulnerabilities  2 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic, Disco  CVE-2019-12781 CVE-2019-12308   If using django via a reverse proxy, which itself would connect to django over HTTPS, if accessing HTTP resources they would not be redirected to HTTPS even if configured to do so on the django server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 38</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-38/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 17:00:00 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-38/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at the latest security updates for the Linux kernel, Firefox, ImageMagick, OpenStack and more, plus we have a special guest, the maintainer and lead developer of the AppArmor project, John Johansen, to talk about the project and some of the upcoming features.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 55 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4031-1] Linux kernel vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Bionic, Cosmic, Disco  CVE-2019-12817   64-bit PowerPC (ppc64el) memory management issue - introduced in the 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 37</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-37/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-37/</guid>
      <description>Overview The big new this week is SackPANIC! updates for the Linux kernel, plus we look at vulnerabilities in, and updates for, Samba, SQLite, Bind, Thunderbird and more, and we are hiring!
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 36 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4017-1, USN-4017-2] Linux kernel vulnerabilities  2 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty ESM, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic, Disco  CVE-2019-11477 CVE-2019-11478   SACK Panic - will be discussed in more detail with Joe later in the show Livepatch (LSN-0052-1) also available for Xenial and Bionic  [USN-4018-1] Samba vulnerabilities  2 CVEs addressed in Disco  CVE-2019-12436 CVE-2019-12435   Two DoS issues (both NULL ptr dereferences) only affecting most recent Samba versions  One in AD DC DNS mgmt server RPC process  Only an authenticated user could trigger this   Other in LDAP server - user with read access to the directory could trigger NULL ptr dereference via the paged search control    [USN-4019-1, USN-4019-2] SQLite vulnerabilities  12 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic, Disco  CVE-2017-2519 CVE-2017-13685 CVE-2017-10989 CVE-2016-6153 CVE-2019-9937 CVE-2019-9936 CVE-2019-8457 CVE-2018-20506 CVE-2018-20346 CVE-2018-20505 CVE-2017-2520 CVE-2017-2518   7 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty ESM  CVE-2017-13685 CVE-2017-10989 CVE-2016-6153 CVE-2019-8457 CVE-2018-20506 CVE-2018-20346 CVE-2017-2518   Mix of various issues, most involving various memory corruption problems  UAFs, DoS (crash), heap-based buffer over-reads (crash -&amp;gt; DoS or possible information disclosure), incorrect use of temporary directories, race-condition leading to NULL pointer dereference, integer overflow -&amp;gt; buffer overflow -&amp;gt; crash / code execution    [USN-4021-1] libvirt vulnerabilities  2 CVEs addressed in Cosmic, Disco  CVE-2019-3886 CVE-2019-10132   DoS where some APIs in the guest agents could be accessed by read-only users - this would cause libvirt to block and cause a DoS Privilege escalation due to insecure permissions on the virt-lockd and virt-logd UNIX domain sockets - these are created by systemd unit files but were created as world writable - and the daemons don&amp;rsquo;t try and authenticate the user - so anyone could use these sockets to potentially elevate privileges - so fixed by ensuring the systemd socket definitions specify the right mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 36</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-36/</guid>
      <description>Overview Security updates for DBus, vim, elfutils, GLib and more, plus Joe and Alex look at another npm package hijack as well as some wider discussions around the big vim RCE of this week.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 43 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4012-1] elfutils vulnerabilities  9 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-7665 CVE-2019-7150 CVE-2019-7149 CVE-2018-18521 CVE-2018-18520 CVE-2018-18310 CVE-2018-16403 CVE-2018-16402 CVE-2018-16062   Mix of issues found via fuzzing with ASAN - all resulting in crash -&amp;gt; DoS from crafted input files  multiple heap-based buffer over-reads in various libraries (libelf, libdw) on crafted ELF input divide-by-zero on crafted ELF input in arlib (used by ar, ranlib and other tools to process .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 35</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-35/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-35/</guid>
      <description>Overview We look at vulnerabilities and updates for Exim, the Linux kernel, Berkeley DB, Qt and more, plus Joe and Alex discuss some recent malware campaigns including Hiddenwasp, and we cover some open positions too.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 34 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-4002-1] Doxygen vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial  CVE-2016-10245   Generates HTML code documentation from code comments Includes a field to search across the documentation Doesn&amp;rsquo;t treat this as untrusted input and blindly displays the input in resulting pages  Allows possible XSS or iframe injection   Fix is simple - whitelist allowed characters to avoid injection etc  [USN-4003-1] Qt vulnerabilities  3 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2018-19873 CVE-2018-19870 CVE-2018-15518   3 likely DoS issues:  Buffer overflow when handling invalid BMP images - didn&amp;rsquo;t check for valid / sensible width or height parameters NULL pointer dereference on malformed GIF images Double free when parsing a specially crafted (illegal format) XML document    [USN-4004-1, USN-4004-2] Berkeley DB vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic, Disco  CVE-2019-8457   Contains an embedded copy of sqlite which was vulnerable to a heap-based out-of-bounds read when handling invalid rtree tables  [USN-4005-1] Linux kernel vulnerabilities  2 CVEs addressed in Disco  CVE-2019-11815 CVE-2019-11810   Reliable Datagram Sockets (RDS) module was vulnerable to a race-condition during network namespace cleanup that could lead to a UAF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 34</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-34/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at security updates for Keepalived, Corosync, GnuTLS, libseccomp and more, plus we talk insider threats with Joe McManus.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 32 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-3976-3, USN-3976-4] Samba regression  Affecting Trusty ESM, Xenial, Bionic Episode 32 - discussed privilege escalation vuln and fix for Samba Original update caused a regression where Samba might crash - fixed  [USN-3994-1] gnome-desktop vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Bionic, Cosmic, Disco  CVE-2019-11460   Thumbnailers could possibly escape bubblewrap sandbox by using TIOCSTI ioctl to send characters to the controlling terminals input buffer and hence escape the sandbox  Requires to compromise a thumbnailer in the first place so less impact Similar to CVE-2019-10063 for flatpak and CVE-2019-7303 for snapd    [USN-3995-1, USN-3995-2] Keepalived vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty ESM, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2018-19115   Heap based buffer overflow when parsing HTTP response code - would potentially write an unlimited amount of attacker controlled data to the heap for a 10-byte long buffer Crash -&amp;gt; DoS, RCE Fixed to properly parse and expect at most a 3 digit long response code  [USN-3845-2] FreeRDP vulnerabilities  6 CVEs addressed in Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2018-8789 CVE-2018-8788 CVE-2018-8787 CVE-2018-8786 CVE-2018-8785 CVE-2018-8784   Back in December published update for FreeRDP (USN-3845-1 - Episode 16)  In Bionic and Cosmic freerdp2 is in main, so that update was for freerdp2 This update is for freerdp (v1), which is in universe in bionic + cosmic Corresponding update    [USN-3997-1] Thunderbird vulnerabilities  14 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic, Disco  CVE-2018-18511 CVE-2019-11698 CVE-2019-9816 CVE-2019-7317 CVE-2019-5798 CVE-2019-9820 CVE-2019-9819 CVE-2019-9817 CVE-2019-9800 CVE-2019-9797 CVE-2019-11693 CVE-2019-11692 CVE-2019-11691 CVE-2019-18511   Thunderbird 60.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 33</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-33/</guid>
      <description>Overview Updated Intel microcode for Cherry + Bay Trial CPUs, fixes for vulnerabilities in curl, Firefox, PHP and MariaDB, plus we talk configuration of virtualised guests to mitigate speculative execution vulnerabilities as well as plans for the Ubuntu 19.10 development cycle.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 43 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-3977-2] Intel Microcode update  4 CVEs addressed in Trusty ESM, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic, Disco  CVE-2019-11091 CVE-2018-12126 CVE-2018-12127 CVE-2018-12130   Corresponding Intel microcode updates for Cherry Trail and Bay Trail CPU families  [USN-3989-1] LibRaw vulnerabilities  7 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2018-5819 CVE-2018-5818 CVE-2018-5817 CVE-2018-20365 CVE-2018-20364 CVE-2018-20363 CVE-2018-20337   Multiple issues fixed:  2*NULL pointer dereference Heap-based buffer overflow Stack-based buffer overflow 3 different cases of possible infinite loop - CPU DoS    [USN-3990-1] urllib3 vulnerabilities  3 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic, Disco  CVE-2019-11324 CVE-2019-11236 CVE-2018-20060   When validating certs for HTTPS, could specify a set of certs to validate against - however it would always include the system CA certs as well - so could validate successfully even if cert is not in chain of explicitly desired set - fixed to NOT include system certs in this case Possible CRLF injection Would possibly expose HTTP authorization credentials across different origin hosts as after authenticating, if being redirected to a different origin host, would still include the Authorization header from the old host to the new host - fixed by ensuring this defaults to being off  [USN-3991-1] Firefox vulnerabilities  17 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic, Disco  CVE-2019-9816 CVE-2019-11698 CVE-2019-11697 CVE-2019-9821 CVE-2019-9820 CVE-2019-9819 CVE-2019-9817 CVE-2019-9814 CVE-2019-9800 CVE-2019-7317 CVE-2019-11701 CVE-2019-11699 CVE-2019-11696 CVE-2019-11695 CVE-2019-11693 CVE-2019-11692 CVE-2019-11691   Latest upstream Firefox release (67.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 32</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-32/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at updates to cover the latest Intel CPU vulnerabilities (MDS - aka RIDL, Fallout, ZombieLoad), plus other vulnerabilies in PostgreSQL, ISC DHCP, Samba and more, whilst special guest this week is Seth Arnold from the Ubuntu Security Team to talk Main Inclusion Review code audits.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 37 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-3972-1] PostgreSQL vulnerabilities  2 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic, Disco  CVE-2019-10130 CVE-2019-10129   Stores statistics for columns by sampling values from that column  Security policy allows to restrict users from viewing particular rows But sampling would not take into account security policy User could craft a leaky operator which would return the sampled data and effectively bypass the security policy Fixed to only allow non-leakproof operators to use sampled data when no relevant row security policies in place   Arbitrary server memory able to be read by executing a crafted INSERT statement on a partitioned table (only affects PostgreSQL 11 so only Disco)  [USN-3973-1] DHCP vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-6470   DHCP server could crash due to mismatch in BIND internal memory management and DHCP server code BIND in Bionic + Cosmic contained a change which zeroed out an internal index to indicate it was unused - however 0 is still a valid index in the DHCP server codebase - and so this could cause a use-after free (since would be free&amp;rsquo;d, index set to 0 by BIND lib but then still used later since 0 is valid).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 31</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-31/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we cover security fixes for GNOME Shell, FFmpeg, Sudo, Ghostscript and others, and we talk to Joe McManus about malicious Dockerhub images, Git repos being ransomed more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 14 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-3966-1] GNOME Shell vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-3820   Local user could potentially bypass various restrictions of the lock screen - menu items can be activated by keyboard combinations - these could then be used to take screenshots (and fill up disk space), close windows behind the lock screen or start the screen reader which could read out the contents of windows behind the lock screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 30</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-30/</guid>
      <description>Overview Fixes for 19 different vulnerabilities across MySQL, Dovecot, Memcached and others, plus we talk to Joe McManus about the recent iLnkP2P IoT hack and the compromise of DockerHub&amp;rsquo;s credentials database and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 19 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-3957-1] MySQL vulnerabilities  8 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic, Disco  CVE-2019-2683 CVE-2019-2632 CVE-2019-2628 CVE-2019-2627 CVE-2019-2614 CVE-2019-2592 CVE-2019-2581 CVE-2019-2566   Latest upstream version 5.7.26 includes fixes for 8 different issues including:  Unauthenticated remote attacker could gain complete access to all MySQL server data Multiple versions of privileged attacker could hang / crash MySQL server    [USN-3958-1] GStreamer Base Plugins vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-9928   Heap based buffer overflow in RTSP connection parser - could allow a malicious server to gain remote code execution on the client - session id can contain attributes separated by semi-colons - would assume when encountering a semi-colon that this delimits the maximum size of the session id - however the session id has a maximum size of 512 bytes - would overflow by using the user-supplied session id length rather than sticking to the maximum structure length - changed to only parse up to the maximum size of the structure to ensure we then don&amp;rsquo;t overflow when copying  [USN-3959-1] Evince vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic, Disco  CVE-2019-11459   Failed to check return values when calling functions for libTIFF - these return the pixel data from an embedded TIFF image - on failure would end up rendering uninitialised memory rather than the TIFF image - fixed to check return values and bail out on error  [USN-3960-1] WavPack vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Bionic, Cosmic, Disco  CVE-2019-11498   Fuzzing via valgrind - found if no sample rate was specified then a stack declared but uninitialized value would be used - could cause a crash etc since could be anything - fixed to initialise it to 0 and to check if still zero before proceeding to process  [USN-3961-1] Dovecot vulnerabilities  2 CVEs addressed in Cosmic, Disco  CVE-2019-11499 CVE-2019-11494   Two issues related to authentication in recent versions of dovecot - if client aborts authentication the serer could crash due to a NULL pointer dereference, and if using TLS but send an invalid authentication message could crash as well  [USN-3962-1] libpng vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-7317   Use after free in png image cleanup - originally was called under png_safe_execute() - this is an internal function which itself calls png_image_free() - so after freeing the image would free it a second time in certain conditions - changed to just call the free function directly rather than via png_safe_execute()  [USN-3963-1] Memcached vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Bionic, Cosmic, Disco  CVE-2019-11596   Possible NULL pointer dereference via local command interface due to insufficient checks when parsing input - commands require 4 input tokens but only checked for 3 (off-by-one) - could allow an attacker with access to the command interface to crash memcached  [USN-3953-2] PHP vulnerabilities  2 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty ESM  CVE-2019-11035 CVE-2019-11034   Episode 29 covered these for standard supported releases - this update is for the ESM releases - two bugs in EXIF tag handling  [USN-3964-1] python-gnupg vulnerabilities  2 CVEs addressed in Bionic, Cosmic, Disco  CVE-2019-6690 CVE-2018-12020   Possible to trick gnupg to decrypt ciphertext other than the intended one when an attacker can control the passphrase to gnupg and the ciphertext is assumed trusted - this uses the command-interface of gnupg and passes the passphrase directly to it - along with the ciphertext - so if attacker includes newlines in the supplied passphrase can then inject their own ciphertext (or plaintext in the context of encryption) - fixed to check passphrase does not contain line-feed or carriage return characters Possible to trick by including what looks like the return response from gnupg directly in the filename to be decrypted when using verbose output mode - fixed by sanitising this filename first  Discussion with Joe McManus about another IoT compromise and DockerHub  https://krebsonsecurity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 29</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-29/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at fixes from the past two weeks including BIND, NTFS-3G, Dovecot, Pacemaker and more, plus we follow up last episodes IoT security discussion with Joe McManus talking about Ubuntu Core. Finally we cover the release of Ubuntu 19.04 Disco Dingo and the transition of Ubuntu 14.04 Trusty Tahr to Extended Security Maintenance.
These past two weeks in Ubuntu Security Updates 53 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-3947-1, USN-3947-2] Libxslt vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-11068   Library to transform XML via XML definitions Includes a security framework since XSLT can define operations to fetch/read/write files and resources etc Various functions would return 0 if an operation is not allowed by the framework which was checked for and correctly disallowed - BUT they could also return -1 on error (say from a potentially bad URL) which would not be caught and so then would proceed and would fetch from the URL in question thereby violating the security policy Fixed to also check for error codes on handle the same as an explicit policy violation  [USN-3948-1] WebKitGTK+ vulnerabilities  14 CVEs addressed in Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-8563 CVE-2019-8559 CVE-2019-8558 CVE-2019-8551 CVE-2019-8544 CVE-2019-8536 CVE-2019-8535 CVE-2019-8524 CVE-2019-8523 CVE-2019-8518 CVE-2019-8506 CVE-2019-8375 CVE-2019-6251 CVE-2019-11070   Wide mix of issues fixed including XSS and DoS attacks or possible arbitrary code execution if visiting a malicious website  [USN-3949-1] OpenJDK 11 vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Bionic  CVE-2019-2422   Backport of openjdk-11 from Disco to Bionic, includes a minor security fix to memory disclosure vulnerablity which could enable an attacker to bypass sandbox  [USN-3918-4] Firefox regressions  17 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-9803 CVE-2019-9793 CVE-2019-9809 CVE-2019-9808 CVE-2019-9807 CVE-2019-9806 CVE-2019-9805 CVE-2019-9802 CVE-2019-9799 CVE-2019-9797 CVE-2019-9796 CVE-2019-9795 CVE-2019-9792 CVE-2019-9791 CVE-2019-9790 CVE-2019-9789 CVE-2019-9788   Episode 26 covered 66.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 28</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-28/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at updates for vulnerabilities in wpa_supplicant, Samba, systemd, wget and more and we talk to Joe about IoT security (or the prevailing lack-thereof).
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 27 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-3939-1, USN-3939-2] Samba vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-3880   Symlink path traversal vulnerability in the Windows Registry service emulation RPC API end-point Allows a local user to create a new registry file anywhere they have Unix permissions to do so within the Samba share  Bypasses share restrictions such as read-only and share ACLs Also allows to create the file outside the share itself if there is already a symlink pointing outside the shared areas   Fixed by removing the ability to save or restore registry keys at all via this RPC API end-point  [USN-3940-1, USN-3940-2] ClamAV vulnerabilities  3 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-1789 CVE-2019-1788 CVE-2019-1787   3 file-handling issues  2 OOB heap read when handling PE (Windows EXE and DLL) and PDF files -&amp;gt; crash -&amp;gt; DoS OOB heap write when scanning OLE2 files (old format Microsoft Office documents), crash -&amp;gt; DoS or possible code execution    [USN-3941-1] Lua vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-6706   UAF if calling debug.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 27</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-27/</guid>
      <description>Overview Carpe Diem for Apache HTTP Server, plus updates for Dovecot, PolicyKit and the Linux kernel, and we talk to Joe McManus about the recent Asus ShadowHammer supply chain attack and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 52 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-3928-1] Dovecot vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-7524   Local user root privilege escalation  Stack buffer overflow - indexer-worker processes missing bounds check when copying from the index If local user can modify the dovecot index then could leverage this for code-execution in the indexer process context Mitigated by usual hardening techniques (ASLR, stack-protector, read-only GOT (via RELRO &amp;amp; BIND_NOW))    [USN-3929-1] Firebird vulnerabilities  2 CVEs addressed in Trusty  CVE-2017-6369 CVE-2014-9323   Remote authenticated users execute code Remote un-authenticated user DoS via op_response action with a non-empty status  [USN-3934-1] PolicyKit vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-6133   Episode 23 - fixed kernel to make process start_time via fork() more atomic Updated policykit to also check UIDs match (so now checks start_time, PID and UID so can&amp;rsquo;t use another user&amp;rsquo;s authorisations)  [USN-3935-1] BusyBox vulnerabilities  10 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-5747 CVE-2018-20679 CVE-2018-1000517 CVE-2017-16544 CVE-2017-15873 CVE-2016-2148 CVE-2016-2147 CVE-2015-9261 CVE-2014-9645 CVE-2011-5325   Mix of issues across various components in BusyBox  udhcpc:  Information disclosure of stack memory in dhcp client / server (shared component) due to failure to check DHCP options are correct size - original fix was incomplete so this got 2 CVEs Heap buffer overflow via DHCP option parsing of OPTION_6RD (IPv6 rapid deployment on IPv4 infra) Integer overflow -&amp;gt; heap-based OOB write -&amp;gt; crash -&amp;gt; DoS / code execution   wget:  Heap buffer overflow in wget   shell:  Failure to sanitize filenames during tab completion - could allow code execution etc as user who is running the shell   archive handling  Integer overflow in bzip2 decompression - OOB write - crash -&amp;gt; DoS / code execution?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 26</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-26/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look security updates for a heap of packages including Firefox &amp;amp; Thunderbird, PHP &amp;amp; QEMU, plus we discuss Facebook&amp;rsquo;s recent password storage incident as well as some listener hardening tips and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 48 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-3919-1] Firefox vulnerabilities  2 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-9813 CVE-2019-9810   Firefox 66.0.1 (mentioned briefly last week) - fixes two vulnerabilities discovered during Pwn2Own Both in the IonMonkey JIT compiler  Incorrect alias information for the Array.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 25</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-25/</guid>
      <description>Overview Ghostscript is back to haunt us for another week, plus we look at vulnerabilities in ntfs-3g, snapd, firefox and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 39 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-3911-1] file vulnerabilities  4 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-8907 CVE-2019-8906 CVE-2019-8905 CVE-2019-8904   4 DoS (crash) found via fuzzing:  Stack overflow in readelf 2 different OOB read due to failure to NULL terminate a string before processing it Read past end of stack due to failing to properly keep track of buffer sizes    [USN-3906-2] LibTIFF vulnerabilities  8 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM  CVE-2019-7663 CVE-2019-6128 CVE-2018-18557 CVE-2018-17101 CVE-2018-17100 CVE-2018-1710 CVE-2018-12900 CVE-2018-10779   Covered in Episode 18 and Episode 24 for standard Ubuntu releases (not all CVEs covered in those updates applicable to Precise ESM)  [USN-3912-1] GDK-PixBuf vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial  CVE-2017-12447   Failure to properly validate BMP image palette parameters - leading to OOB when decoding colormap later on  [USN-3914-1] NTFS-3G vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-9755   Discovered recently by Chris Coulson during code-audit of ntfs-3g - actually had been fixed upstream late last year but no CVE assigned Heap buffer overflow able to be triggered when mounting a filesystem onto a mount point with path name greater than PATH_MAX, and from a current working directory which has a path name also greater than PATH_MAX Contents of buffers is attacker controlled so heap can be overflown with attacker controlled input - likely to leverage into arbitrary code execution Contrived example BUT in Debian and Ubuntu ntfs-3g is setuid root - which then leads to root privilege escalation with arbitrary code execution Update was released within hours of the bug being made public to fix the heap buffer overflow Currently testing ntfs-3g as not-setuid root to release in a future update to avoid any other possible privilege escalation bugs in the future  [USN-3915-1] Ghostscript vulnerabilities  2 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-3838 CVE-2019-3835   Similar to previous CVE, forceput operator could be extracted from the DefineResource method to allow access to the file-system outside of the -dSAFER sandbox superexec operator was available in the internal dictionary - also able to be extracted and hence used to access files outside the sandbox  [USN-3913-1] P7ZIP vulnerabilities  2 CVEs addressed in Xenial  CVE-2017-17969 CVE-2016-2335   Heap based OOB write when decompressing a crafted ZIP file (crash -&amp;gt; DoS, possible code execution) Heap based OOB read when decompressing a UDF file (universal disk format - used for DVD images) - crash, DoS  [USN-3918-1] Firefox vulnerabilities  17 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-9803 CVE-2019-9793 CVE-2019-9809 CVE-2019-9808 CVE-2019-9807 CVE-2019-9806 CVE-2019-9805 CVE-2019-9802 CVE-2019-9799 CVE-2019-9797 CVE-2019-9796 CVE-2019-9795 CVE-2019-9792 CVE-2019-9791 CVE-2019-9790 CVE-2019-9789 CVE-2019-9788   Almost latest Firefox release (this is 66, 66.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 24</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-24/</guid>
      <description>Overview A look at recent fixes for vulnerabilities in poppler, WALinuxAgent, the Linux kernel and more. We also talk about some listener feedback on Ubuntu hardening and the launch of Ubuntu 14.04 ESM.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 18 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-3905-1] poppler vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-9200   Heap-based buffer underwrite (index into array using negative index) - write into heap memory which preceeds the intended buffer - heap corruption - crash -&amp;gt; DoS, possible code execution Found by fuzzing and AddressSanitizer in clang  [USN-3906-1] LibTIFF vulnerabilities  6 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-7663 CVE-2019-6128 CVE-2018-19210 CVE-2018-17000 CVE-2018-12900 CVE-2018-10779   All DoS, one possible code-execution:  Dereference of an invalid address (read from invalid memory location) Heap buffer overread 2x NULL pointer dereferences Memory leak Heap buffer overflow - possible code execution    [USN-3907-1] WALinuxAgent vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-0804   WALinuxAgent used to manage instances of Ubuntu (and other Linux distributions) running on Azure Can be used to configure swap space for a given image  would then create a swap file (/mnt/swapfile) BUT would make it world-readable so any local user could read it - if keys or other sensitive items were in memory that got swapped to disk could be read by all   Fixed to make this readable only by root and to also correct the permissions on any existing swapfile as well  [USN-3902-2] PHP vulnerabilities  4 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM  CVE-2019-9023 CVE-2019-9021 CVE-2019-9024 CVE-2019-9020   See last week&amp;rsquo;s Episode 23 - discussed for Xenial and Trusty - fixed now for Precise ESM as well  [USN-3910-1, USN-3910-2] Linux kernel vulnerabilities  5 CVEs addressed in Xenial and Trusty (Xenial HWE)  CVE-2019-6133 CVE-2018-7740 CVE-2018-19985 CVE-2018-1120 CVE-2017-18241   2 of these discussed in previous episodes Episode 23 (PolicyKit start time, DoS via mmaping a FUSE-backed file into processes memory containing command-line args) Trigger of BUG_ON() in kernel (like assert() for kernel code) due to integer overflow from large pgoff parameter to remap_file_pages() when used in conjuction with an existing mmap() -&amp;gt; crash -&amp;gt; DoS OOB read in USB driver for Option High Speed mobile devices - would read a descriptor from the USB device as a u8 and then index into an array with this without checking whether it fell within the array NULL pointer dereference in f2fs driver via use of noflush_merge mount option  [USN-3908-1, USN-3908-2] Linux kernel vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty and Precise ESM (Trusty HWE)  CVE-2019-6133   See last week&amp;rsquo;s Episode 23 - discussed for Bionic kernel - now for Trusty kernel (and the Trusty HWE kernel backported to Precise ESM)  PolicyKit start time issue, fixed in kernel    [USN-3909-1] libvirt vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-3840   NULL pointer dereference in libvirt if agent does not reply in time (say guest is being shutdown) - crash host libvirt -&amp;gt; DoS  Goings on in Ubuntu Security Community Ubuntu Hardening Response  Alexander Popov  Responsible for getting STACKLEAK into the mainline kernel Pointed out his Linux Kernel Defence Map and kconfig hardened check We use kconfig hardened check internall and tyhicks has contributed various improvements which allow this to be used to check the various Ubuntu kernel configurations    Extended Security Maintenance for Ubuntu 14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 23</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-23/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at security updates for the Linux kernel, PHP and NVIDIA drivers, revealing recent research into GPU based side-channel attacks plus we call for suggestions on hardening features and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 10 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-3885-2] OpenSSH vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-6111   Originally covered in Episode 20 (malicious server could overwrite local client files) Previous fix was incomplete - missing a patch  [USN-3901-1, USN-3901-2] Linux kernel vulnerabilities  3 CVEs addressed in Bionic, Trusty &amp;amp; Xenial (Bionic HWE kernel)  CVE-2019-6133 CVE-2018-19854 CVE-2018-18397   2 out of 3 from Jann Horn   PolicyKit provides ability to authorise an application to perform privileged actions</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 22</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-22/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we cover security updates including Firefox, Thunderbird, OpenSSL and another Ghostscript regression, plus we look at a recent report from Capsule8 comparing Linux hardening features across various distributions and we answer some listener questions.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 16 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-3893-2] Bind vulnerabilities  2 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM  CVE-2019-6465 CVE-2018-5745   Covered last week in Episode 21 for regular Ubuntu releases  [USN-3866-3] Ghostscript regression  Affecting Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic Mentioned last week briefly Previous update to Ghostscript introduced a regression (blue background)  See later for information    [USN-3894-1] GNOME Keyring vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial  CVE-2018-20781   Already fixed upstream (hence doesn&amp;rsquo;t apply to Bionic / Cosmic etc) User&amp;rsquo;s login password kept in memory of child process after pam session is opened Could be dumped by root user or captured in crash dump etc and possibly exposed  Other tools exist to try and extract from memory as well (minipenguin etc)   Fix is to simply reset this after pam session is opened  [USN-3895-1] LDB vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-3824   LDAP-like embedded database (used by Samba and others) Authenticated user can cause OOB read when searching LDAP backend of AD DC with a search string containing multiple wildcards - crash -&amp;gt; DoS  [USN-3896-1] Firefox vulnerabilities  3 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-5785 CVE-2018-18511 CVE-2018-18356   Firefox 65 Use-after-free and integer overflow in Skia library (vector graphics library, similar to cairo) Cross-origin image theft - able to read from canvas element in violation of same-origin policy using transferFromImageBitmap() method  [USN-3897-1] Thunderbird vulnerabilities  7 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2018-18509 CVE-2018-18505 CVE-2018-18501 CVE-2019-5785 CVE-2018-18500 CVE-2018-18356 CVE-2016-5824   Thunderbird 60.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 21</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-21/</guid>
      <description>Overview Double episode covering the security updates from the last 2 weeks, including snapd (DirtySock), systemd and more, plus we talk responsible disclosure and some open positions on the Ubuntu Security team.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 15 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-3886-1] poppler vulnerabilities  2 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-7310 CVE-2018-20551   Two DoS:  Out-of-bounds heap buffer read due to missing check for a negative index -&amp;gt; crash -&amp;gt; DoS Crash due to hitting an assertion -&amp;gt; DoS    [USN-3888-1] GVfs vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-3827   Possible to allow a local user with admin privileges (eg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 20</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-20/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at Linux kernel updates for all releases, OpenSSH, dovecot, curl and more. Plus we answer some frequently asked questions for Ubuntu security, in particular the perennial favourite of why we choose to just backport security fixes instead of doing rolling package version updates to resolve outstanding CVEs.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 33 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-3871-3, USN-3871-4, USN-3871-5] Linux kernel vulnerabilities  13 CVEs addressed in Bionic and Xenial (HWE - backport of Bionic kernel to Xenial)  CVE-2018-9516 CVE-2018-19407 CVE-2018-18281 CVE-2018-17972 CVE-2018-16882 CVE-2018-14625 CVE-2018-10883 CVE-2018-10880 CVE-2018-10882 CVE-2018-10878 CVE-2018-10877 CVE-2018-10879 CVE-2018-10876   Last week (Episode 19) covered kernel update for Bionic in preparation for 18.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 19</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-19/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at updates to the Linux kernel in preparation for the 18.04.2 release, plus updates for Open vSwitch, Firefox, Avahi, LibVNCServer and more. We also revisit and discuss upstream changes to the mincore() system call to thwart page-cache side-channel attacks first discussed in Episode 17.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 40 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-3870-1] Spice vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-3813   Out-of-bounds read - off-by-one - likely crash on segmentation violation but possible code-execution  [USN-3871-1] Linux kernel vulnerabilities  13 CVEs addressed in Bionic  CVE-2018-9516 CVE-2018-19407 CVE-2018-18281 CVE-2018-17972 CVE-2018-16882 CVE-2018-14625 CVE-2018-10883 CVE-2018-10880 CVE-2018-10882 CVE-2018-10878 CVE-2018-10877 CVE-2018-10879 CVE-2018-10876   NULL pointer dereference in KVM able to be triggered by a local user (crash -&amp;gt; DoS) mremap() TLB flush leaving stale entries in page cache - covered previously in Episode 15 Episode 15 covered CVE-2018-17972 (procfs kernel stack disclosure) UAF in KVM when using nested virtualisation (not enabled by default for Ubuntu kernels) able to be trigered by gust VM to crash host (DoS) or possibly elevate privileges etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 18</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-18/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at some details of the 46 unique CVEs addressed across the supported Ubuntu releases and take a deep dive into the recent apt security bug.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 46 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-3863-1, USN-3863-2] APT vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-3462   MITM allowing RCE as root in the context of apt Due to mishandling of HTTP redirect which would allow malicious mirror / MITM to inject content and then could allow arbitrary command execution Fixed by simply disallowing control characters in HTTP redirect responses  See detailed discussion later in show    [USN-3864-1] LibTIFF vulnerabilities  7 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2018-8905 CVE-2018-7456 CVE-2018-18661 CVE-2018-18557 CVE-2018-17101 CVE-2018-17100 CVE-2018-10963   Multiple NULL pointer dereferences and assertion failures (crash -&amp;gt; DoS) Multiple heap-based buffer overflows and an integer overflow (crash -&amp;gt; DoS / possible RCE)  [USN-3865-1] poppler vulnerabilities  2 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2018-20650 CVE-2018-20481   Assertion failure and NULL pointer dereference triggered by crafted PDFs (crash -&amp;gt; DoS)  [USN-3707-2] NTP vulnerabilities  9 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM  CVE-2018-7185 CVE-2018-7183 CVE-2017-6463 CVE-2017-6462 CVE-2016-9311 CVE-2016-9310 CVE-2016-7428 CVE-2016-7427 CVE-2016-7426   NTP updated for Bionic, Artful, Xenial and Trusty in July 2018 - this is the corresponding update for Precise ESM Multiple issues including: RCE in ntpq from a crafted response from the server, various DoS at both protocol level between client and server (disrupt a client talking to server) and at application level (to crash the application)  [USN-3866-1] Ghostscript vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2019-6116   Another week, another Ghostscript vulnerability courtesy of Tavis Ormandy (GPZ) (after a random look at the latest GS release 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 17</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-17/</guid>
      <description>Overview First episode of 2019! This week we look &amp;ldquo;System Down&amp;rdquo; in systemd, as well as updates for the Linux kernel, GnuPG, PolicyKit and more, and discuss a recent cache-side channel attack using the mincore() system call.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 51 unique CVEs addressed across the supported Ubuntu releases.
[USN-3846-1, USN-3847-1, USN-3847-2, USN-3847-3] Linux kernel vulnerabilities  Kernel updates as part of normal 3-weekly SRU cycle - includes various fixes across the supported releases  CVE-2018-18710 (Cosmic, Bionic, Bionic HWE, Xenial, Xenial HWE, Trusty, Trusty HWE) CVE-2018-18690 (Bionic, Bionic HWE, Xenial, Xenial HWE, Trusty, Trusty HWE) CVE-2018-18445 (Bionic, Bionic HWE) CVE-2018-16276 (Bionic, Bionic HWE) CVE-2018-14734 (Bionic, Bionic HWE) CVE-2018-12896 (Bionic, Bionic HWE, Xenial, Xenial HWE, Trusty, Trusty HWE) CVE-2017-18174 (Xenial, Xenial HWE) CVE-2018-10902 (Trusty, Trusty HWE) CVE-2017-2647 (Trusty, Trusty HWE)   Info leak in CDROM driver, XFS DoS via writing of extended attributes causing an error condition that leaves the fs in an error state until next mount Bounds check bypass in BPF verifier (mentioned in Episode 15) Incorrect bounds checking in Yurex USB driver (Episode 7) UAF in infiniband -&amp;gt; Crash -&amp;gt; DoS Integer overflow in POSIX timers overrun accounting due to type confusion (int vs 64-bit signed) Double free in AMD GPIO pinctrl driver - DoS / privilege escalation Race condition in midi driver - double free -&amp;gt; privilege escalation NULL pointer dereference in kernel keyring -&amp;gt; crash -&amp;gt; DoS  [LSN-0046-1] Linux kernel livepatch for vulnerabilities  10 CVEs addressed in  CVE-2018-16658 CVE-2018-16276 CVE-2017-5753 CVE-2018-9363 CVE-2018-18690 CVE-2018-10880 CVE-2018-14734 CVE-2018-18445 CVE-2018-10902 CVE-2018-18710    [USN-3850-1] NSS vulnerabilities  3 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2018-12404 CVE-2018-12384 CVE-2018-0495   Cache side-channel variant of Bleichenbacher attack (http://cat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 16</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-16/</guid>
      <description>Overview Last episode for 2018! This week we look at CVEs in lxml, CUPS, pixman, FreeRDP &amp;amp; more, plus we discuss the security of home routers as evaluated by C-ITL.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 21 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-3841-1, USN-3841-2] lxml vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty, Xenial, Bionic  CVE-2018-19787   Popular XML/HTML parser for Python Tries to remove clean input document and remove links (to say embedded javascript code) - but doesn&amp;rsquo;t account for links containing escaped characters - so link could persist Similar to CVE-2014-3146  In this case tried to account for whitespace in links but didn&amp;rsquo;t include all possible whitespace characters    [USN-3842-1] CUPS vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2018-4700   Session cookies used for authentication to CUPS web interface used only the current time in seconds as a seed for the relatively predictable PRNG  Easy to bruteforce / guess Fix ensures to use current time value including microseconds Still using relatively predictable PRNG - should use /dev/urandom etc    [USN-3837-2] poppler regression  2 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2018-19149 CVE-2018-16646   Previous poppler update (Episode 15) - fix missed a previous commit and so regressed (crash on opening certain PDF files)  [USN-3843-1, USN-3843-2] pixman vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty  CVE-2015-5297   Low level library for pixel manipulation (used by X, Wayland, Qemu etc) Pointer overflow leading to stack-based buffer overflow in computing bounds of pixel buffers  Did include a check to see if was inside bounds, BUT didn&amp;rsquo;t account for possible overflow in arithmetic before the check Need to check for possible overflow before doing arithmetic and comparison    [USN-3844-1] Firefox vulnerabilities  10 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2018-18497 CVE-2018-18495 CVE-2018-18498 CVE-2018-18494 CVE-2018-18493 CVE-2018-18492 CVE-2018-17466 CVE-2018-12407 CVE-2018-12406 CVE-2018-12405   Firefox 64 - multiple security vulnerabilities fixed  Buffer overflows, UAFs, same-origin-policy violation, webextensions able to violate restrictions, various memory safety / corruption bugs https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 15</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-15/</guid>
      <description>Overview Security updates for 29 CVEs including Perl, the kernel, OpenSSL (PortSmash) and more, plus in response to some listener questions, we discuss how to make sure you always have the latest security updates by using unattended-upgrades.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 29 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-3834-1, USN-3834-2] Perl vulnerabilities  4 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2018-18314 CVE-2018-18313 CVE-2018-18312 CVE-2018-18311   Perl regex engine fuzzed with valgrind to detect memory errors  2 different heap based buffer overflow in regex engine Heap-based read past end of buffer in regex engine   Integer overflow from environment variables  uses untrusted input from environment variables (length of values to calculate memory to allocate) heap buffer overflow    [USN-3835-1, USN-3836-1, USN-3836-2] Linux kernel vulnerabilities   6 CVEs addressed in Cosmic, 2 in Bionic and Xenial</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 14</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-14/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at some details of the 32 unique CVEs addressed across the supported Ubuntu releases and talk open source software supply chain integrity and how this relates to Ubuntu compared to the recent npm event-stream compromise.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 32 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-3826-1] QEMU vulnerabilities  10 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2018-19364 CVE-2018-18954 CVE-2018-18849 CVE-2018-17963 CVE-2018-17962 CVE-2018-17958 CVE-2018-16847 CVE-2018-12617 CVE-2018-11806 CVE-2018-10839   7 medium, 3 low priority  Integer overflow in virtual network interface driver, able to be triggered by user process in guest -&amp;gt; crash -&amp;gt; DoS Heap based buffer overflow in SLiRP, user-based networking stack (default) during reassembly of fragmented datagrams Integer overflow when reading large blocks from files - nice PoC on github NVMe emulator missing checks on read / write parameters - OOB heap buffer r/w - guest user/process could trigger -&amp;gt; DoS (crash) or possible arbitrary code execution on host as qemu process Integer type mismatch in rtl8139 and pcnet drivers - (from size_t to int) - unsigned to signed - INT_MAX -&amp;gt; -ve -&amp;gt; OOB read - crash / DoS  Copy-pasta?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 13</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-13/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at some details of the 16 unique CVEs addressed across the supported Ubuntu releases and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 16 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-3816-2] systemd vulnerability  3 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2018-15687 CVE-2018-15686 CVE-2018-6954   Episode 12 - original fix for CVE-2018-6954 was incomplete - this includes the complete fix Also includes an update to avoid a possible hang on shutdown in unattended-upgrades - LP #1803391  During shutdown, systemd is already in the process of shutting down Then unattended-upgrades runs and it goes and tries to update systemd - which then tries to reexec it - which blocks waiting for it to finish shutting down Creates a deadlock since systemd is waiting on unattended-upgrades to finish but u-u is waiting on systemd reexec Fix is to not do reexec if systemd is already in the process of stopping    [USN-3825-1, USN-3825-2] mod_perl vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2011-2767   Old CVE - reported to Debian in 2011, who assigned a CVE internally but didn&amp;rsquo;t go any further with it Recently the original reporter of the vulnerability submitted a patch to Debian to fix it - so vuln was reported to Mitre Now fixed in Ubuntu as well  [USN-3801-2] Firefox regressions  12 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2018-12397 CVE-2018-12396 CVE-2018-12395 CVE-2018-12403 CVE-2018-12402 CVE-2018-12401 CVE-2018-12399 CVE-2018-12398 CVE-2018-12393 CVE-2018-12392 CVE-2018-12390 CVE-2018-12388   Firefox update (v63) (Episode 9) had some minor regressions  These were present in the upstream firefox release itself   This provides 63.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 12</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-12/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at some details of the 33 unique CVEs addressed across the supported Ubuntu releases, including some significant updates for systemd and the kernel, plus we talk about even more Intel side-channel vulnerabilities and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 33 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-3814-1] libmspack vulnerabilities  2 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2018-18585 CVE-2018-18584   Out of bounds write of 1 byte when a CAB file uses the maximum Quantum block size - buffer overflow, DoS -&amp;gt; crash, possible code execution Failure to validate filenames properly - could accept a filename with embedded NUL bytes - possible DoS -&amp;gt; crash  [USN-3815-1, USN-3815-2] gettext vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM, Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2018-18751   Double free for specially crafted translations file, DoS -&amp;gt; crash, possible code execution via heap corruption etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 11</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-11/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at some details of the 23 unique CVEs addressed across the supported Ubuntu releases, discuss the latest purported Intel side-channel vulnerability PortSmash and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 23 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-3806-1] systemd vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2018-15688   Reported by Felix Wilhelm from Google Security Team to Ubuntu in LP #1795921 systemd contains DHCPv6 client written from scratch Heap buffer overflow in DHCPv6 option handling (say via server id of &amp;gt;=493 bytes) Coordinated with systemd upstream and Red Hat to resolve this  [USN-3807-1] NetworkManager vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2018-15688   NetworkManager contains the same code taken from systemd-networkd so is also vulnerable  [USN-3808-1] Ruby vulnerabilities  2 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic and Cosmic  CVE-2018-16395 CVE-2018-16396   Misuses return value when comparing names in X509 certificates  If returned 1 on comparing name would assume are identical but are in fact not Could allow to impersonate a certificate   Taint flags not propagated when unpacking arrays into strings, or packing strings into arrays  Could allow untrusted data to be treated as trusted    [USN-3809-1] OpenSSH vulnerabilities  2 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic  CVE-2018-15473 CVE-2016-10708   User enumeration due to fail to bail out early on invalid user authentication  Would take longer to process a packet with a valid username than an invalid one Can determine account names as a result via brute-force timing attack   Possible to crash the per-connection process on NULL pointer dereference  Low priority since doesn&amp;rsquo;t crash the main daemon so not really a DoS    [USN-3786-2] libxkbcommon vulnerabilities  11 CVEs addressed in Bionic  CVE-2018-15856 CVE-2018-15864 CVE-2018-15863 CVE-2018-15862 CVE-2018-15861 CVE-2018-15859 CVE-2018-15858 CVE-2018-15857 CVE-2018-15855 CVE-2018-15854 CVE-2018-15853   Episode 7 for Trusty and Xenial Some common CVEs, some new ones specific to Bionic version  [USN-3810-1] ppp vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic  CVE-2018-11574   Ubuntu specific change to pppd to add support for EAP-TLS authentication  Could be triggered on both peer or server side Lack of input validation coupled with an integer overflow lead to crash and possible authentication bypass Leads to memcpy() with a negative length value (and hence very large unsigned value) Theoretically possible to overwrite other data structures related to server state and therefore bypass authentication    [USN-3811-1] SpamAssassin vulnerabilities  3 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic  CVE-2018-11781 CVE-2018-11780 CVE-2017-15705   Updated to latest stable version of spamassassin (3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 10</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-10/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at some details of the 17 unique CVEs addressed across the supported Ubuntu releases, have a brief look at some Canonical presentations from LSS-EU and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 17 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-3799-2] MySQL vulnerabilities  3 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM  CVE-2018-3282 CVE-2018-3174 CVE-2018-3133   Ubuntu 12.04 Precise ESM update for 3 CVEs fixed in usual supported releases (covered in Episode 9)  [USN-3803-1] Ghostscript vulnerabilities  3 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2018-18284 CVE-2018-18073 CVE-2018-17961   More ghostscript vulnerabilities!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 9</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-9/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at some details of the 61 unique CVEs addressed across the supported Ubuntu releases, with a particular focus on the recent Xorg vulnerability (CVE-2018-14665), plus Cosmic is now officially supported by the Security Team.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 61 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-3790-2] Requests vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Cosmic  CVE-2018-18074   Cosmic is now officially released and so is officially supported by the Security Team This is the same vulnerability which we covered in Episode 8 for Trusty, Xenial, Bionic now fixed for Cosmic  [USN-3795-2] libssh vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Cosmic  CVE-2018-10933   This is the same vulnerability which we covered in Episode 8 for Trusty, Xenial, Bionic now fixed for Cosmic  [USN-3792-3] Net-SNMP vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Cosmic  CVE-2018-18065   This is the same vulnerability which we covered in Episode 8 for Trusty, Xenial &amp;amp; Bionic now fixed for Cosmic  [USN-3796-3] Paramiko vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Cosmic  CVE-2018-1000805   This is the same vulnerability which we covered in Episode 8 for Trusty, Xenial &amp;amp; Bionic now fixed for Cosmic  [USN-3788-2] Tex Live-bin vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Cosmic  CVE-2018-17407   This is the same vulnerability which we covered in Episode 7 for Trusty, Xenial &amp;amp; Bionic now fixed for Cosmic  [USN-3797-1, USN-3797-2] Linux kernel vulnerabilities  4 CVEs addressed in Xenial and Trusty for the Xenial HWE kernel for Trusty  CVE-2018-10938 CVE-2018-9363 CVE-2018-16658 CVE-2018-14734   Includes:  UAF in Infiniband -&amp;gt; DoS via crash Integer overflow in CDROM -&amp;gt; info disclosure of kernel memory Integer overflow in bluetooth HID -&amp;gt; buffer overflow -&amp;gt; DoS / possible arbitrary code execution Remotely triggerable infinite loop in labelled network handler (CIPSO)  CIPSO used by SELinux / SMACK not AppArmor so unlikely Ubuntu users affected      [USN-3798-1] Linux kernel vulnerabilities  8 CVEs addressed in Trusty and Precise ESM (for the Trusty HWE kernel for Precise ESM)  CVE-2018-9518 CVE-2018-7566 CVE-2018-1000004 CVE-2017-18216 CVE-2017-15299 CVE-2017-0794 CVE-2016-7913 CVE-2015-8539   Includes:  Local DoS / code exec via insertion of an already existing key into kernel keyring UAF in XCeive driver, local DoS / code exec (crash) Race condition in generic SCSI -&amp;gt; Local DoS (crash) / code exec NULL ptr dereference in ocfs2 -&amp;gt; Local DoS (crash) Race condition in ALSA handling of ioctls -&amp;gt; Local DoS via deadlock Race condition in ALSA -&amp;gt; UAF / out of bounds read -&amp;gt; Local DoS (crash) / code exec Buffer overflow in NFC LLCP impl -&amp;gt; remote DoS / code exec    [USN-3777-3] Linux kernel (Azure) vulnerabilities  8 CVEs addressed in Xenial, Bionic  CVE-2018-6555 CVE-2018-6554 CVE-2018-3639 CVE-2018-14633 CVE-2017-5715 CVE-2018-15572 CVE-2018-15594 CVE-2018-17182   Corresponding fixes for Azure Cloud specific kernel as covered in Episode 7 for standard Bionic kernel  [USN-3799-1] MySQL vulnerabilities  21 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic, Cosmic  CVE-2018-3284 CVE-2018-3283 CVE-2018-3282 CVE-2018-3278 CVE-2018-3277 CVE-2018-3276 CVE-2018-3251 CVE-2018-3247 CVE-2018-3200 CVE-2018-3187 CVE-2018-3185 CVE-2018-3174 CVE-2018-3173 CVE-2018-3171 CVE-2018-3162 CVE-2018-3161 CVE-2018-3156 CVE-2018-3155 CVE-2018-3144 CVE-2018-3143 CVE-2018-3133   New upstream versions of MySQL for all supported releases to fix multiple vulnerabilities, add features and possible incompatible changes Trusty: 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 8</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-8/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at some details of the 15 unique CVEs addressed across the supported Ubuntu releases and discuss some of the security relevant changes in Ubuntu 18.10, plus a refresh of the Ubuntu CVE tracker and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 15 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-3790-1] Requests vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic  CVE-2018-18074   Requests library could end up sending credentials in clear text if server is configured with a https -&amp;gt; http redirect  [USN-3792-1, USN-3792-2] Net-SNMP vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic &amp;amp; Precise ESM  CVE-2018-18065   Remote DoS via a NULL pointer dereference from an authenticated attacker  [USN-3793-1] Thunderbird vulnerabilities  5 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic  CVE-2018-12385 CVE-2018-12383 CVE-2018-12378 CVE-2018-12377 CVE-2018-12376   New Thunderbird version (60) containing 5 fixes Interestingly all of these were also vulnerabilities in Firefox - in particular CVE-2018-12383 was discussed in Episode 4 for Firefox  [USN-3794-1] MoinMoin vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic  CVE-2017-5934   XSS in link editor dialog allow injection of arbitrary web content (HTML, scripts etc)  [USN-3789-2] ClamAV vulnerabilities  5 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM  CVE-2018-15378 CVE-2018-14682 CVE-2018-14681 CVE-2018-14680 CVE-2018-14679   Corresponding fix for Precise ESM from ClamAV which we discussed in Episode 7 Also rolls in fixes for 4 other vulnerabilities in the embedded mspack library  In trusty and precise we used the embedded libmspack, newer releases use the system package so weren&amp;rsquo;t affected    [USN-3795-1] libssh vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic  CVE-2018-10933   Embedded SSH server and client implementation Allows bypass of authentication by remote attackers if they send a SSH2_MSG_USERAUTH_SUCCESS message instead of the SSH2_MSG_USERAUTH_REQUEST message to initiate the authentication process This message is meant to be sent from the server to the client but in this case are sending it to the server State machine on server-side then jumps straight to &amp;lsquo;Authenticated&amp;rsquo; Only affects applications which use libssh as a server  [USN-3796-1, USN-3796-2] Paramiko vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic &amp;amp; Precise ESM  CVE-2018-1000805   Python SSH library for both servers and clients Very similar to CVE-2018-10933 for libssh - remote authentication bypass by presenting SSH2_MSG_USERAUTH_SUCCESS in place of SSH2_MSG_USERAUTH_REQUEST Due to code-reuse between client and server implementations On server side, runs the normal client side code to be used when receiving this authentication success from the server, and flips the &amp;lsquo;authenticated&amp;rsquo; flag - which is shared by both the server and client code  Goings on in Ubuntu Security Community Ubuntu 18.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 7</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-7/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at some details of the 78 unique CVEs addressed across the supported Ubuntu releases including more GhostScript, ImageMagick, WebKitGTK, Linux kernel and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 78 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-3773-1] Ghostscript vulnerabilities  2 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic  CVE-2018-17183 CVE-2018-16510   Similar to [USN-3768-1] from Episode 5  [USN-3769-2] Bind vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM  CVE-2018-5740   Extended Security Maintenance version of [USN-3769-1]  [USN-3774-1] strongSwan vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic  CVE-2018-17540   [USN-3771-1] incorporated fixes for multiple CVEs - but these fixes themselves introduced this new vulnerability Heap buffer overflow found by Google&amp;rsquo;s OSS-Fuzz leading to DoS for gmp plugin  [USN-3775-1, USN-3775-2, USN-3776-1, USN-3776-2, USN-3777-1, USN-3777-2] Linux kernel vulnerabilities  11 CVEs addressed across Precise ESM, Trusty, Xenial and Bionic including HWE kernels  CVE-2018-6555 CVE-2018-6554 CVE-2018-14633 CVE-2018-14634 CVE-2018-15572 CVE-2018-15594 CVE-2018-16276 CVE-2018-10902 CVE-2018-10853 CVE-2017-18216 CVE-2018-17182   Not all CVEs affect all releases Includes:  UAF and memory leak -&amp;gt; DoS in IRDA Stack buffer overwrite in iSCSI - low chance of privilege escalation Integer overflow leading to possible privilege escalation but only on machines with &amp;gt;32GB RAM Insufficiencies discovered in various Spectre variant mitigations previously deployed Incorrect bounds checking in yurex USB driver from userspace -&amp;gt; crash / privilege escalation for local user Race condition in midi driver - double free -&amp;gt; privilege escalation KVM hypervisor instruction emulation fail to check privileges - privilege escalation inside guest OCFS2 file-system driver NULL pointer dereference -&amp;gt; BUG (mutex logic bug) Memory management sequence number overflow leading to UAF -&amp;gt; possible privilege escalation - Jann Horn (GPZ)    [USN-3780-1] HAProxy vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Bionic  CVE-2018-14645   Out of bounds read leading to remote crash -&amp;gt; DoS  [USN-3781-1] WebKitGTK+ vulnerabilities  24 CVEs addressed in Bionic  CVE-2018-4361 CVE-2018-4359 CVE-2018-4358 CVE-2018-4328 CVE-2018-4323 CVE-2018-4319 CVE-2018-4318 CVE-2018-4317 CVE-2018-4316 CVE-2018-4315 CVE-2018-4314 CVE-2018-4312 CVE-2018-4311 CVE-2018-4309 CVE-2018-4306 CVE-2018-4299 CVE-2018-4213 CVE-2018-4212 CVE-2018-4210 CVE-2018-4209 CVE-2018-4208 CVE-2018-4207 CVE-2018-4197 CVE-2018-4191   Used by many GNOME applications to render web content (Epiphany, Evolution, Boxes, GThumb, Buidler, Empathy, etc) Many issues fixed in this release including, XSS, DoS, RCE etc  [USN-3782-1] Liblouis vulnerabilities  2 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic  CVE-2018-17294 CVE-2018-12085    [USN-3778-1] Firefox vulnerabilities  3 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic  CVE-2018-12387 CVE-2018-12386 CVE-2018-12385   Firefox 62 release - includes fixes for RCE, local cache poisoning and information disclosures  [USN-3783-1] Apache HTTP Server vulnerabilities  3 CVEs addressed in Bionic  CVE-2018-11763 CVE-2018-1333 CVE-2018-1302   DoS (crash) via incorrect stream destruction and DoS (resources) from incorrect frame handling  [USN-3785-1] ImageMagick vulnerabilities  14 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic  CVE-2017-13144 CVE-2018-16749 CVE-2018-16645 CVE-2018-16644 CVE-2018-16643 CVE-2018-16642 CVE-2018-16323 CVE-2018-14551 CVE-2018-16750 CVE-2018-16640 CVE-2018-14437 CVE-2018-14436 CVE-2018-14435 CVE-2018-14434   Disables support for using PS and PDF from Ghostscript in ImageMagick due to large number of GS vulns (see Episode 5) Also multiple fixes for ImageMagick itself, including memory leaks (DoS), information disclosure, RCE etc  [USN-3784-1] AppArmor update  Hardening of various AppArmor profiles (mentioned in Episode 5)  [LSN-0044-1] Linux kernel vulnerability  Livepatch incorporating L1TF, Spectrev2 and other fixes as well  [USN-3786-1] libxkbcommon vulnerabilities  11 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial  CVE-2018-15864 CVE-2018-15863 CVE-2018-15862 CVE-2018-15861 CVE-2018-15859 CVE-2018-15858 CVE-2018-15857 CVE-2018-15856 CVE-2018-15855 CVE-2018-15854 CVE-2018-15853   Loads keyboard descriptions from disk - multiple vulnerabilities in file format handling leading to DoS etc  [USN-3787-1] Tomcat vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial  CVE-2018-11784   Redirect handling allowed attacker to redirect to any URI of their choice Can be avoided if had manually enabled both mapperDirectoryRedirectEnabled and mapperContextRootRedirectEnabled  [USN-3789-1] ClamAV vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic  CVE-2018-15378   Crash in handling of unpacked MEW executable files  [USN-3788-1] Tex Live vulnerabilities  2 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic  CVE-2018-17407 CVE-2015-5700   File overwrite via insecure symlink handling Code execution via buffer overflow in Type1 font handler  [USN-3791-1] Git vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic  CVE-2018-17456   RCE when cloning a malicious repository - due to insufficient validation of git submodule URLs and paths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 6</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-6/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at some details of the 17 unique CVEs addressed across the supported Ubuntu releases and more.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 17 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-3771-1] strongSwan vulnerabilities  4 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic  CVE-2018-5388 CVE-2018-16152 CVE-2018-16151 CVE-2018-10811   2 CVEs: flaws in RSA implementation allow Bleichenbacher-style attacks in parsing of the ASN.1 encoded digestInfo strongSwan implementation was too lenient and would allow arbitrary random data to be contained following various elements in the ASN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 5</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-5/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at some details of the 43 unique CVEs addressed across the supported Ubuntu releases and talk about the recently announced Extended Security Maintenance support for Ubuntu 14.04 Trusty Tahr.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 43 unique CVEs addressed across the various supported releases of Ubuntu (Bionic, Xenial, Trusty and Precise ESM)
[USN-3762-1, USN-3762-2] Linux kernel vulnerabilities  2 CVEs addressed in Bionic and corresponding HWE kernel for Xenial  CVE-2017-13695 CVE-2018-1118   Both information disclosure vulnerabilities which could allow exposure of kernel addresses  Not directly an issue but could be used to defeat ASLR when combined with another vulnerability    [USN-3763-1] Linux kernel vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM  CVE-2018-5390   SegmentSmack (see episode 0)  [LSN-0043-1] Linux kernel vulnerability  Livepatch to fix multiple vulnerabilities fixed in previous kernel package updates  [USN-3764-1] Zsh vulnerabilities  3 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic  CVE-2018-1100 CVE-2018-13259 CVE-2018-0502   2 issues in shebang / hashbang handling  shebang lines longer than 64 bytes truncated - could execute wrong interpreter mishandling of some particular formatted shebang lines which could execute interpreter from second line of file   Stack based buffer-overflow allowing code execution in the context of a different user  [USN-3747-2] OpenJDK 10 regression  4 CVEs addressed in Bionic  CVE-2018-2972 CVE-2018-2952 CVE-2018-2826 CVE-2018-2825    [USN-3761-2, USN-3761-3] Firefox regressions  5 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic  CVE-2018-12383 CVE-2018-12378 CVE-2018-12377 CVE-2018-12376 CVE-2018-12375   Previous update to latest firefox resulted in issues due to language packs missing (and hence missing spellcheck dictionaries) and use of wrong search provider  [USN-3765-1, USN-3765-2] curl vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic and Precise ESM  CVE-2018-14618   Similar to previous CVE-2017-8816 - integer overflow in calculations during NTLM authentication could allow heap buffer overflow and hence RCE Uses the password length in this calculation (which is supplied by the attacker) so relatively easy to trigger  [USN-3722-5] ClamAV regression  2 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic  CVE-2018-0361 CVE-2018-0360    [USN-3766-1, USN-3766-2] PHP vulnerabilities  3 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic and Precise ESM  CVE-2018-14883 CVE-2018-14851 CVE-2015-9253   Integer overflows in JPEG and EXIF handlers leading to out-of-bounds reads and hence crash - DoS php-fpm (FastCGI process manager) - alternative FastCGI implementation for PHP - could cause DoS since didn&amp;rsquo;t restart child processes correctly - then consume CPU and disk space (via logging) - only fixed in Bionic for now  [USN-3722-6] ClamAV vulnerabilities  2 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM  CVE-2018-0361 CVE-2018-0360    [USN-3767-1, USN-3767-2] GLib vulnerabilities  2 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic and Precise ESM  CVE-2018-16429 CVE-2018-16428   Issues with markup parsing  [USN-3768-1] Ghostscript vulnerabilities  16 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic  CVE-2018-16802 CVE-2018-16585 CVE-2018-16543 CVE-2018-16542 CVE-2018-16541 CVE-2018-16540 CVE-2018-16539 CVE-2018-16513 CVE-2018-16511 CVE-2018-16510 CVE-2018-16509 CVE-2018-15911 CVE-2018-15910 CVE-2018-15909 CVE-2018-15908 CVE-2018-11645   Ghostscript is used to process Postscript (and other formats) - PS is Turing Complete so in general is unsafe Hence Ghostscript includes a sandbox (-dSAFER) to try and prevent issues with handling of untrusted files Tavis Ormandy previously found a number of issues in the SAFER sandbox which allowed escape from it and execution of commands (ie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 4</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-4/</guid>
      <description>Overview A quieter week in package updates - this week we look at some details of the 9 unique CVEs addressed across the supported Ubuntu releases and talk about various hardening guides for Ubuntu.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 9 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-3759-1] libtirpc vulnerabilities  3 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic  CVE-2017-8779 CVE-2018-14622 CVE-2016-4429   Transport Independent RPC Library, used by NFS 1 medium priority issue:  Crash from NULL pointer dereference when run out of file descriptions (failure to check return value) - a remote attacker could cause crash by flooding with new connections   2 low priority issues:  &amp;ldquo;rpcbomb&amp;rdquo; - allows an unauthenticated attacker to DoS via memory exhaustion Stack based buffer overflow could cause a crash when flooded by ICMP and UDP packets in the sunrpc implementation - fixed by replacing stack based memory allocation with heap-based allocation instead Common pattern to fix this type of issue - similar work in Linux kernel recently by KSPP to replace VLAs    [USN-3759-2] libtirpc vulnerabilities  3 CVEs addressed in Precise ESM  CVE-2017-8779 CVE-2018-14622 CVE-2016-4429   Same as above for the Precise Extended Security Maintenence release  [USN-3760-1] transfig vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial  CVE-2018-16140   transfig / fig2dev - utilities for converting XFig files Fixes an error which allows memory corruption when handling specially crafted files  [USN-3761-1] Firefox vulnerabilities  5 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic  CVE-2018-12383 CVE-2018-12378 CVE-2018-12377 CVE-2018-12376 CVE-2018-12375   Latest firefox release (62) fixing a number of issues including DoS and RCE One interesting one is CVE-2018-12383 - in Firefox 58 the password storage format was changed (was sqlite, then was changed to json).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 3</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-3/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week we look at 29 unique CVEs addressed across the supported Ubuntu releases, a discussion of the Main Inclusion Review process and recent news around the bubblewrap package, and open positions within the team.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates 29 unique CVEs addressed
[USN-3756-1] Intel Microcode vulnerabilities  3 CVEs addressed in Trusty, Xenial, Bionic  CVE-2018-3640 CVE-2018-3639 CVE-2018-3646   Intel microcode updates to address L1TF, Spectre Variant 4 and Rogue System Register Read (RSRE) Intel initially released this with a brand new license which included terms around disallowing benchmarking and possibly preventing redistribution via the Ubuntu mirrors  As a result, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t provide updated microcode packages to full address L1TF etc Intel have now reverted back to the license used on previous microcode packages and so this can now finally be released   https://perens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 2</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-2/</guid>
      <description>Overview 83 unique CVEs addressed across the supported Ubuntu releases.
This week in Ubuntu Security Updates [USN-3742-3] Linux kernel (Trusty HWE) regressions  Security team issues USNs for package updates caused by regressions in previous security updates Fix for regressions caused by the original kernel update for L1TF Could cause Java applications to fail to start and possible kernel panics on boot for some hardware configurations  [USN-3745-1] wpa_supplicant and hostapd vulnerability  1 CVEs addressed in Bionic  CVE-2018-14526   Researchers analysed WPA2 4-way handshake via symbolic execution to find weaknesses  Found a number of issues including a decryption oracle In this case, the would decrypt but not authenticate frame and then could allow recovery of the group key via a timing side-channel In theory, allows an unauthenticated attacker to recover WPA2 group key via frame manipulation when used with TKIP  NOTE: is not advised to use TKIP in practice anyway (should use WPA2/CCMP) and so should have limited applicability   In practice, due to large number of attempts needed to recover the full key, this is impractical (especially given that the group key is changed periodically)   https://w1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 1</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-1/</guid>
      <description>Overview  Security fixes for 39 CVEs this week including L1TF and FragmentSmack  This week in Ubuntu Security Updates GDM (USN-3737-1) (CVE-2018-14424)  Found by Ubuntu Security Team member Chris Coulson during audit of gdm3 source code Local user can exploit via DBus to crash GDM via use-after-free (create a transient display which is automatically cleaned up, then try to query info for the previously created display) Bionic only so far  libarchive (USN-3736-1)  6 CVEs addressed across Bionic, Xenial and Trusty  CVE-2016-10209 CVE-2016-10349 CVE-2016-10350 CVE-2017-14166 CVE-2017-14501 CVE-2017-14503   All local crashes / DoS / unspecified impact via specially crafted archives in various formats  Samba (USN-3738-1)  4 CVEs addressed across Bionic, Xenial and Trusty  CVE-2018-10858 CVE-2018-10918 CVE-2018-10919 CVE-2018-1139   Includes vulnerabilities in both the samba client and server  Likely to affect most Ubuntu users    libxml2 (USN-3739-1) (USN-3739-2)  XML parsing library used across lots of different software packages 5 CVEs fixed across releases for Bionic, Xenial and Trusty  2 CVEs fixed for Precise ESM CVE-2016-9318 CVE-2017-16932 CVE-2017-18258 CVE-2018-14404 CVE-2018-14567   Includes information disclosure and DoS  L1TF and FragmentSmack vulnerabilities in Linux Kernel (USN-3740-1) (USN-3740-2) (USN-3741-1) (USN-3741-2) (USN-3742-1) (USN-3742-2) L1TF (CVE-2018-3620) (CVE-2018-3646)  Latest speculative execution cache side channel attack affecting Intel processors Allows to access contents from L1 Data Cache via speculative execution, can then be read by cache side channel 3 variants, SGX, SMM and VMM but only 2 affect Ubuntu Processors access virtual addresses which need to be translated to physical addresses Page Table Entries map from one to the other (contains metadata of page including offset and present bit) Pages can be swapped in our out of memory (Present or not) - so if not present then need to do a full page table walk to look up physical address But Intel processor will use offset value from PTE even on non-present pages speculatively For non-present pages, this value is usually junk so can essentially speculatively read arbitrary memory from L1D cache depending on PTE value SGX doesn&amp;rsquo;t affect Ubuntu since not used SMM fixed via ensuring PTEs of not present pages always refer to non-cacheable memory and hence can&amp;rsquo;t be used for this VMM is trickier  VMs maintain their own PTEs so also need to ensure they are doing the right thing OR if running untrusted VMs need to do a full L1D flush on switching from host to VM   Made more trickier by Hyper Threading since sibling hyper-threads share the L1D cache So if have different trust domains on sibling hyper-threads may have to disable HT in certain circumstances  FragmentSmack (CVE-2018-5391)  Last week was SegmentSmack in TCP fragment reassembly, this week is FragmentSmack Similar but for IP fragmentation reassembly  Exploiting high algorithmic complexity of IP fragment reassembly code paths to cause DoS    GnuPG (USN-3733-2) (CVE-2017-7526)  Last week GnuPG was fixed for Xenial and Trusty for RSA cache side-channel issue This is corresponding fix for Precise ESM  WebKitGTK+ vulnerabilities (USN-3743-1)  14 CVEs fixed in web content renderer used in many desktop apps  CVE-2018-12911 CVE-2018-4246 CVE-2018-4261 CVE-2018-4262 CVE-2018-4263 CVE-2018-4264 CVE-2018-4265 CVE-2018-4266 CVE-2018-4267 CVE-2018-4270 CVE-2018-4272 CVE-2018-4273 CVE-2018-4278 CVE-2018-4284   Fixes for Bionic and Xenial  PostgreSQL (USN-3744-1) (CVE-2018-10915) (CVE-2018-10925)  2 CVEs fixed in popular relational database across Bionic, Xenial and Trusty  procps-ng (USN-3658-3)  3 CVEs fixed in Precise ESM procps-ng package  CVE-2018-1122 CVE-2018-1123 CVE-2018-1125    Linux kernel livepatch (LSN-0042-1)  No Livepatch possible for L1TF so a LSN to advise to do an update and reboot  Goings on in Ubuntu Security Community Hiring Ubuntu Security Manger  https://boards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 0</title>
      <link>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubuntusecuritypodcast.org/episode-0/</guid>
      <description>Introduction What will be covered  Overview of latest security updates for Ubuntu In depth discussion of trending CVEs Other things the team has been up to  This week in Ubuntu Security Updates SegmentSmack (CVE-2018-5390) (USN-3732-1)  DoS via expensive algorithmic computation in TCP stream reassembly Requires attacker to have an existing TCP session Affecting kernel &amp;gt;= 4.9 Fixed in Bionic and Xenial for HWE No known exploits in the wild  linux kernel (LSN-0041-1)  brief description of livepatch Several issues (5 CVEs)  stack overflow in SCSI / cdrom layers (CVE-2018-11506) DoS / crash via specially crafted ext4 filesystem (CVE-2018-1094) files can be created with group permissions which the original owner did not have within sgid directories (CVE-2018-13405)  Originally reported by Jann Horn in relation to whoopsie / apport in Ubuntu   DoS / crash via specially crafted xfs filesystem (CVE-2018-13094) SegmentSmack fix (CVE-2018-5390)   generic &amp;amp; lowlatency kernels for Trusty, Xenial and Bionic  gnupg (CVE-2017-7526) (USN-3733-1)  Cache side-channel attack on RSA implementation When CVE was created, only assigned to libgcrypt gnupg quietly announced 1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
